<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/</link><description>Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 12:42:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTM - OpenAdmin</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/htm-openadmin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 12:42:29 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/htm-openadmin/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/OpenAdmin.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The importance to also patch your &ldquo;applications&rdquo;, and not just your services.
Recon Again, this is an HTB box, so recon is mainly active, and I feel like activ recon == enum.
Still, we can check :
 Name of the box : OpenAdmin ; OS &ldquo;type&rdquo;, : Linux : Hints given on HTB website, information section :   
Enum As always, we start with an nmap scan :]]></description></item><item><title>HTB - Blue</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/htb-blue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:37:44 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/htb-blue/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/Blue.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A good ol' vuln to get starting!
This will be my first real tutorial, so I&rsquo;ll try to explain the basics of what I am doing. Please bear in mind that I am very new to haking, probably like you are. I am merely sharing my knowledge and by doing so I am making sure I inderstood what I did. Please correct me if you find anything wrong, or ask question if you need to!]]></description></item><item><title>Starting my hacking journey, hopefully!</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/starting-my-hacking-journey-hopefully/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:21:29 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/starting-my-hacking-journey-hopefully/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/hacker-2300772_1280-870x500.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>It&rsquo;s been a while since I wrote here, hopefully I will be able to write more often and hopefully too I will be able to finally get into hacking properly.
Bosom buddies I have been interested by InfoSec for many years. It mostly started a bit more than 10 years ago when I was reading a lot about pentesting : Kali was called BackTrack then, I played a lot with it and MetaSploit.]]></description></item><item><title>Hello FastMail, Goodbye ProtonMail</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/hello-fastmail-goodbye-protonmail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 09:58:54 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/hello-fastmail-goodbye-protonmail/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2019/03/Hello-FastMail-Goodbye-ProtonMail.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>After a bit more than a year using ProtonMail, I couldn&rsquo;t bear it anymore&hellip; I was really pissed by its lack of &ldquo;usability&rdquo;. Even though I had almost 1 year left, I made the switch to FastMail, and I couldn&rsquo;t have been happier. Let me explain.
ProtonMail isn&rsquo;t bad&hellip; However, there is a few issues, that overtime really grew over me.
First and foremost, the non standard protocols! ProtonMail doesn&rsquo;t use IMAP(s)/SMTP(s).]]></description></item><item><title>Manage VMware snapshots with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/manage-vmware-snapshots-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 08:48:46 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/manage-vmware-snapshots-with-powercli/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2018/12/Manage-VMware-snapshots-with-PowerCLI.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Manually taking a snapshot under VMware is easy : connect to the HTML5 Web UI, find the server from the list, right click, select Snapshot, Name it&hellip; However, when you have to do it several times in a row, it becomes really frustrating. Let&rsquo;s see how to improve that.
Here comes PowerCLI VMware released an awesome (and I am Linux guy) tool to manage your virtual machines from the command line.]]></description></item><item><title>Install GLPI on Ubuntu 18.04 with MariaDB and NGinX</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-glpi-on-ubuntu-18.04-with-mariadb-and-nginx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:18:42 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-glpi-on-ubuntu-18.04-with-mariadb-and-nginx/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2018/12/Install-GLPI-on-Ubuntu-18.04-with-MariaDB-and-NGinX.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>GLPI is an asset management software. It can handle automatic inventory of your assets (workstations, servers, printers, etc.) ticketing, and much more. Let&rsquo;s see how to install it under Ubuntu with MariaDB and NGinX.
Prepare your system Simply install the requirements :
sudo apt install nginx php7.0-fpm mariadb-server php7.0-curl php7.0-gd php7.0-mysql php7.0-cli php7.0-imap php7.0-ldap php7.0-apcu php7.0-xmlrpc php7.0-mbstring php7.0-xml php7.0-xmlrpc Create the self signed certificates :
cd /etc/ssl/certs sudo openssl req -x509 -newkey rsa:4096 -keyout private/gpli.]]></description></item><item><title>Automagically deploy apps with GPO and Boxstarter</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 14:03:32 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/boxstarter.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A few days ago, I talked about Ninite, which is an awesome tool to deploy several Windows apps easily. However, if you want to use it on a Windows domain (likely in your company), you&rsquo;ll have to get the Pro (and paid version). Hopefully, with BoxStarter, you can do it for free. Let me show you how I do it.
Let&rsquo;s do some scripting! In my case, I want all my users to have the same &ldquo;base apps&rdquo; installed on their systems.]]></description></item><item><title>All your devices are belong to Ubiquity</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/all-your-devices-are-belong-to-ubiquity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 16:48:01 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/all-your-devices-are-belong-to-ubiquity/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/unifi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I love tech and I love to try new tech stuff. Recently, I have been playing with some network gear from Ubiquiti. For a reasonable price, you&rsquo;ll get enterprise grade gear. Is it really that good? Let&rsquo;s check my non-unboxing review.
A bit of background I am a frequent reader of Mr Troy Hunt and when I read his article a few years ago about the Unifi suite that made want to try it again, a little.]]></description></item><item><title>Install Windows programs like a boss with Ninite</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 23:36:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/ninite.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Do you remember how you used to install programs under Windows several years ago? Next, next, next&hellip; Are you still doing it the exact same way today? If that&rsquo;s so, I may have something of interest for you, keep reading !
Windows' programs' installation is so painful I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I am quite pissed off with the way &ldquo;software&rdquo; works on Windows. Let&rsquo;s say you want to install VLC to watch movies, then you have to fire up your web browser, go to VLC website (probably via a search engine), find the correct version (32 or 64 bits), download the product, and install it.]]></description></item><item><title>Watch Netflix US from anywhere in the world</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/watch-netflix-us-from-anywhere-in-the-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 14:08:19 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/watch-netflix-us-from-anywhere-in-the-world/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/netflix.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>As you may know, Netflix offers different catalogs of movies and TV shows that are &ldquo;country based&rdquo;. It means, that if you are watching Netflix from the US, you&rsquo;ll only get access to the US catalog. If you are, in the UK, then you&rsquo;ll only have access to the UK catalog and so on. Since there is quite a lot of differences between those catalogs it can be interesting to have access to all of them.]]></description></item></channel></rss>