<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>plex - Catégorie - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/plex/</link><description>plex - Catégorie - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 07:15:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/plex/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automatically download subtitles with Plex</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automatically-download-subtitles-with-plex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 07:15:33 +0200</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automatically-download-subtitles-with-plex/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/auto_dl_sub_plex.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Today, there is hundreds (if not thousands) of TV shows and movies. I enjoy a lot of them, and I enjoy them in their original version. Unfortunately, I am not fluent in every languages. Fortunately enough, we have autmomatic subtitles for Kodi and a similar system of automatic subtitles for Plex. Let&rsquo;s see how to use it.
In plugins, we trust  Open your web browser and go to your Plex server, most probably here.]]></description></item><item><title>Synchronize your media with Plex Trakt plugin</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/synchronize-your-media-with-plex-trakt-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:08:08 +0200</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/synchronize-your-media-with-plex-trakt-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/trakt.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Remember a few days ago when we decided to synchronize our watched media between Kodi and Trakt? Well, today, we’ll do the same with Plex Media Center!
Synchronize Plex and Trakt.tv Basically, all you need to do is:
download the latest version of the plugin, from here. Place it in the Plex Plug-ins directory Restart Plex Inside Plex (from a web browser), go to Channel, and click on the little gear on the Trakt image: At the top, you’ll see an URL from Trakt.</description></item><item><title>What are good Kodi alternatives?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/what-are-good-kodi-alternatives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 01:56:46 +0200</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/what-are-good-kodi-alternatives/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_alternatives.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>We, at Streaming Generation, love Kodi and talk a lot about it. However, there are good Kodi alternatives out there. Let us guide you through three of our favourites options.
Plex Plex works differently than Kodi. It is composed of two parts. One server and one client.
Basically, it means you’ll install the Plex Server on the computer (or even better, on the NAS) where you media files are located.</description></item></channel></rss>