<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>linux - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/linux/</link><description>linux - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:18:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/linux/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install GLPI on Ubuntu 18.04 with MariaDB and NGinX</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-glpi-on-ubuntu-18.04-with-mariadb-and-nginx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:18:42 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-glpi-on-ubuntu-18.04-with-mariadb-and-nginx/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2018/12/Install-GLPI-on-Ubuntu-18-04-with-MariaDB-and-NGinX.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>GLPI is an asset management software. It can handle automatic inventory of your assets (workstations, servers, printers, etc.) ticketing, and much more. Let&rsquo;s see how to install it under Ubuntu with MariaDB and NGinX.
Prepare your system Simply install the requirements :
sudo apt install nginx php7.0-fpm mariadb-server php7.0-curl php7.0-gd php7.0-mysql php7.0-cli php7.0-imap php7.0-ldap php7.0-apcu php7.0-xmlrpc php7.0-mbstring php7.0-xml php7.0-xmlrpc Create the self signed certificates :
cd /etc/ssl/certs sudo openssl req -x509 -newkey rsa:4096 -keyout private/gpli.]]></description></item><item><title>Using Unifi controller on Docker</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/using-unifi-controller-on-docker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 18:04:27 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/using-unifi-controller-on-docker/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/unifi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Following a post on Reddit, I decided to share my config used to run the Unifi controller. Doing so, you won&rsquo;t have to purchase a Unifi Cloud Controller.
Spoiler alert&hellip; I no longer use Unifi hardware, and I&rsquo;ll share why in a future post.
System Overview I have 2 servers :
 local server at home, which runs the Unifi controller in a Docker swarm setup ; remote server online, which runs the NGiNX reverse proxy.]]></description></item><item><title>Nesatmo : beautiful graphs for Netatmo</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/nesatmo-beautiful-graphs-for-netatmo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 09:32:28 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/nesatmo-beautiful-graphs-for-netatmo/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/netatmo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Netatmo are little, funny, useless devices that monitor &ldquo;stuff&rdquo; in your home.
Netatmo weather On the weather side, you can buy an indoor / outdoor station :
The indoor station is connected to your WiFi connection for the &ldquo;data&rdquo; part and to a power line for&hellip; power!
The outdoor station, runs on batteries and is wirelessly connected to the indoor (aka, base) station. Batteries should last several months.
Usually, I am not much into proprietary solution but I have to admit that this solution is pretty convenient.]]></description></item><item><title>Scan to PDF with command line under GNU/Linux</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/scan-to-pdf-with-command-line-under-gnu/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 12:01:12 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/scan-to-pdf-with-command-line-under-gnu/linux/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/scan_pdf_cli.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>After years of not-so-good services, I deciced to replace my old Canon MG5550 printer/scanner combo. Instead, I bought a simple black and white laser printer/scanner, and I have never been so happy with a &ldquo;printer&rdquo;.
More info about the printer Recently, I needed to go through quite some paperwork and I knew it would be a hassle (and pricey) do it with my actual hardware. Moreover, I was never happy with it: it was not reliable under Linux, there was no auto document feeder, etc.]]></description></item><item><title>Sending text messages from your computer</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 11:12:57 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/send_text_from_pc.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Do you hate touchscreen? I sure do! More than touchscreen, I hate when I have to write something using a touch screen. This is why, I have been trying and using different solutions that allows me to send text messages from my computer with a real (mechanical) keyboard!
Foreword Please note that this guide is based on Android phones and is desktop &ldquo;OS&rdquo; agnostic.
If you are using Apple phones and computers, then have a look here.]]></description></item><item><title>How to set up correct Freenas jail permissions</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-set-up-correct-freenas-jail-permissions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 12:14:03 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-set-up-correct-freenas-jail-permissions/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/freenas.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Freenas is a great software, allowing you to turn a PC into a NAS. Is it totally free and open source, which we really like.
Freenas overview Like any “market” NAS, Freenas allows you to install third party software such as bitorrent client, or newsgroups client. One of my favorite tools for downloading media (once again, make sure this is legal where you live) is actually a suite of tools based on newsgroups.</description></item><item><title>NZBGet as a replacement of Sabnzbdplus</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/nzbget-as-a-replacement-of-sabnzbdplus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 12:55:43 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/nzbget-as-a-replacement-of-sabnzbdplus/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/nzbget.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>After years of Sabnzbdplus’s reign, a new tool doing for the same purpose was born: NZBGet. In a few words, NZBGet has a lighter footprint on your system. It is coded in C++ whereas Sab is coded in Python. This means that NZBGet will run better on smaller system (such as NAS).
Configuring NZBGet can be pretty tricky for the first time, especially if you want to combine it with Couchpotato and Sickbeard and leave to them the post processing / renaming.</description></item></channel></rss>