<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>chromebook - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/chromebook/</link><description>chromebook - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:15:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/chromebook/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Kodi on your Chromebook with Android</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-your-chromebook-with-android/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:15:26 +0200</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-your-chromebook-with-android/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2016/04/Chromebook.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>A few days ago, I wrote a new guide in order to show you a <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/directly-install-kodi-on-your-chromebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">new, easier and more reliable method to install Kodi on any Chromebook</a> using crouton. Now, if you are lucky, your Chromebook might be elligible to install the Android Play Store&hellip; Let&rsquo;s see if that&rsquo;s is the case and if it is, we will see how to install Kodi using the Android Play Store on your Chromebook.</p>
<h2 id="is-my-chromebook-elligible-to-instal-android-play-store">Is my Chromebook elligible to instal Android Play Store?</h2>
<p>First, of, check this <a href="https://sites.google.com/a/chromium.org/dev/chromium-os/chrome-os-systems-supporting-android-apps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">(official) link</a>. If is says &ldquo;Stable channel&rdquo; for you model, then you are all good, go to the next step.</p>
<p>If not, all hope ain&rsquo;t lost. For example, I own an Asus C200, and official status is set to &ldquo;Planned&rdquo;. However, by turning using the &ldquo;dev&rdquo; channel, I can now use Android apps on my Chromebook.</p>
<p>In order to make sure if your Chromebook is elligible or not, we will now <a href="https://support.google.com/chromebook/answer/1086915?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">turn on the dev channel</a>.</p>
<p>Once the update is done, your computer will reboot. If the Android PLay Store is available, then you&rsquo;ll notice a new icon for the Android Play Store in the bar at the bottom of the screen.</p>
<h2 id="install-android-apps-on-your-chromebook">Install Android Apps on your Chromebook</h2>
<p>So, you have the Play Store icon in the icon bar at the bottom of the screen? Great, click on it, and let the computer make the first set-up. I&rsquo;ll take a few minutes.</p>
<p>Once the update is over, simply click on Play Store icon one more time, and search for Kodi :</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now, simply install it :</p>
<p></p>
<p>That&rsquo;s it! You now have the latest Kodi version installed with no pain.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Directly Install Kodi on your Chromebook</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/directly-install-kodi-on-your-chromebook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 13:56:38 +0200</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/directly-install-kodi-on-your-chromebook/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2016/04/Chromebook.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Thanks to <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/install-latest-kodi-chromeos/#comment-3496118744" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Zach</a>, we now have a great way to install Kodi on our Chromebook.</p>
<h2 id="switch-your-chromebook-to-developpers-mode">Switch your Chromebook to developper&rsquo;s mode</h2>
<p>In order to install Kodi on Chrome OS, we’ll need to install a proper Linux system. Don’t worry, this is done easily thanks to the <a href="https://github.com/dnschneid/crouton" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">crouton</a> script.</p>
<p><strong>NB : be aware that turning developer’s mode ON, will delete ALL your data on the device!</strong></p>
<p>First of all you have to turn on the developer’s mode on your device. Let’s do it!</p>
<ol>
<li>While the computer is powered on. Press Esc + Refesh + Power ;</li>
<li>Device will reboot with a warning message, hit CTRL + D to continue;</li>
<li>Then hit Enter to confirm the Developer’s mode;</li>
<li>Device will reboot again, hit again CTRL + D to proceed.</li>
</ol>
<p>NB : every time you see that bugging screen at boot, you can pass it with CTRL+D</p>
<p>What really bugs me with developers mode, is that you have to press CTRL+D on each cold boot or it’ll emits a double bip, and takes more time to boot (so that you can read and re read, and re re read, the warning screen).</p>
<h2 id="install-kodi-on-your-chromebook">Install Kodi on your Chromebook</h2>
<p>Now that you are in developer’s mode, you are ready to install Linux with crouton. But what is Crouton? Crouton is a tool that will enable to create “chroot” installation a various Linux distribution. Basically, a “chroot” is a bit like a virtual machine, or box that sits inside your computer and allows you to run another (or several) “virtual” computer inside your physical one.</p>
<p>In our case, it will allow us to install a “real” Linux inside the ChromeOS. Which means we will have a full standard working computer inside the limited ChromeOS computer. We will call this, our Kodi instance.</p>
<p>Your computer should be “brand new”, with no data at all in it. Set ip up as usual with your Google account and Wi-Fi settings. Then, the fun starts.</p>
<ul>
<li>Open Chrome browser;</li>
<li>Download the latest version of crouton, <a href="http://goo.gl/fd3zc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">right here</a>;</li>
<li>Hit CTRL + ALT + T (it will open a new scary tab in Chrome), this is called a terminal emulator;</li>
<li>Enter</li>
</ul>
<p><code>shell</code></p>
<p>The “shell” appearance should slightly change;</p>
<ul>
<li>Enter the following command to create the “chroot”.</li>
</ul>
<p><code>sudo sh ~/Downloads/crouton -t kodi -n kodi</code></p>
<p>NB : with -t being the &ldquo;target&rdquo; and -n the name of the instance.</p>
<p>Wait for the process to complete, it will take a few minutes and text will scroll on your screen. Don’t close the tab, but you can keep you using your computer / navigating on other tabs.</p>
<p>At some point, inside the tab we ran the previous command, <strong>it will ask you for a login and password</strong>. Enter anything you like, it doesn’t have to be your Google credentials. Actually, it is even better if you use any other credentials. You’ll then use them to log in Linux. The way it works, when you are prompted for your password, nothing will seem to happen. This is expected. Just enter you password once, hit Enter and confirm it.</p>
<p>Wait for the process to finish.</p>
<h2 id="and-thats-it-">And… that’s it !</h2>
<p>Now every time you want to run Kodi, open a Shell in Chrome by hitting <strong>CTRL+ALT+T</strong> and just type :</p>
<p><code>sudo startkodi</code></p>
<p>That&rsquo;s it! Kodi should start up, and run with the sound and everything working as expected!</p>
<p><strong>NB</strong> : please note that in order to have sound, your sound must be turned on both on the &ldquo;ChromeOS&rdquo; side, and the Kodi instance.</p>
<p>NB : you can switch from/to ChromeOS and from/to Kodi instance by hitting CTRL + ALT + SHIFT + Forward (or Backward). Forward and Backward are the keys on the right of the Esc key. You might have to press it a couple of times, for it to work.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Install the Latest Kodi on ChromeOS</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-the-latest-kodi-on-chromeos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 12:00:17 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-the-latest-kodi-on-chromeos/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2016/04/Chromebook.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Android promised several months ago to add <a href="https://sites.google.com/a/chromium.org/dev/chromium-os/chrome-os-systems-supporting-android-apps?hl=en&amp;rd=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Android support to ChromeOS devices</a>. However, this is taking ages… For now, if you want to use Kodi on ChromeOS, your only solution is to use Crouton in order to install the latest Kodi on ChromeOS.</p>
<p>NB : you can find on older version of this tutorial in order to <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-chromebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">install Kodi on a Chromebook</a>.</p>
<h2 id="prepare-the-beast">Prepare the beast</h2>
<p>In order to install Kodi on Chrome OS, we’ll need to install a proper Linux system. Don’t worry, this is done easily thanks to the <a href="https://github.com/dnschneid/crouton" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">crouton</a> script.</p>
<p><strong>NB : be aware that turning developer’s mode ON, will delete ALL your data on the device!</strong></p>
<p>First of all you have to turn on the developer’s mode on your device. Let’s do it!</p>
<ol>
<li>While the computer is powered on. Press Esc + Refesh + Power ;</li>
<li>Device will reboot with a warning message, hit CTRL + D to continue;</li>
<li>Then hit Enter to confirm the Developer’s mode;</li>
<li>Device will reboot again, hit again CTRL + D to proceed.</li>
</ol>
<p>NB : every time you see that bugging screen at boot, you can pass it with CTRL+D</p>
<p>What really bugs me with developers mode, is that you have to press CTRL+D on each cold boot or it’ll emits a double bip, and takes more time to boot (so that you can read and re read, and re re read, the warning screen).</p>
<h2 id="set-up-linux-with-crouton">Set up linux with crouton</h2>
<p>Now that you are in developer’s mode, you are ready to install Linux with crouton. But what is Crouton? Crouton is a tool that will enable to create “chroot” installation a various Linux distribution. Basically, a “chroot” is a bit like a virtual machine, or box that sits inside your computer and allows you to run another (or several) “virtual” computer inside your physical one.</p>
<p>In our case, it will allow us to install a “real” Linux inside the ChromeOS. Which means we will have a full standard working computer inside the limited ChromeOS computer.</p>
<p>Your computer should be “brand new”, with no data at all in it. Set ip up as usual with your Google account and Wi-Fi settings. Then, the fun starts.</p>
<ul>
<li>Open Chrome browser;</li>
<li>Download the latest version of crouton, <a href="http://goo.gl/fd3zc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">right here</a>;</li>
<li>Hit CTRL + ALT + T (it will open a new scary tab in Chrome), this is called a terminal emulator;</li>
<li>Enter</li>
</ul>
<p>shell</p>
<p>The “shell” appearance should slightly change;</p>
<p>Please note the “ <strong>-n kodi</strong> ” flag (see next step) which allows us to name our chroot “kodi”. If you already have followed our previous guide, then you replace kodi by another name since it has to be unique. You can choose anything you like, just avoid spaces in the name. Then, you’ll have to use that name you just set up everywhere in this guide instead of the default “kodi” name.</p>
<p>Another solution, would be to delete the old <strong>kodi</strong> “chroot”. However, I would only do that if it doesn’t work at all. In order to do so, enter the following command:</p>
<p>sudo delete-chroot kodi</p>
<p>Ok, so you either deleted your old Kodi “chroot” or decided to rename the one we are about to create to something else.</p>
<ul>
<li>Enter the following command to create the “chroot”.</li>
</ul>
<p>sudo sh ~/Downloads/crouton -r sid -t xfce -n kodi</p>
<p>Wait for the process to complete, it will take a few minutes and text will scroll on your screen. Don’t close the tab, but you can keep you using your computer / navigating on other tabs.</p>
<p>At some point, inside the tab we ran the previous command, <strong>it will ask you for a login and password</strong>. Enter anything you like, it doesn’t have to be your Google credentials. Actually, it is even better if you use any other credentials. You’ll then use them to log in Linux. The way it works, when you are prompted for your password, nothing will seem to happen. This is expected. Just enter you password once, hit Enter and confirm it.</p>
<p>Now, to run the Linux you just installed, you have to enter another command inside the “shell” tab.</p>
<p>Hit:</p>
<p>sudo enter-chroot -n kodi</p>
<p>You are now inside the “chroot’. It is a bit like a virtual machine, or like you installed a brand new computer inside your Chrome OS device. Which means, you now have 2 devices in one : Chrome OS is there, always, unchanged. And an extra “Linux” system you can run when you want to.</p>
<p>Let’s see how to install latest Kodi on Chrome OS, our last step.</p>
<h2 id="install-latest-kodi-on-chrome-os">Install Latest Kodi on Chrome OS</h2>
<p>You’ll notice that the prompt line start with (kodi). It means you are “inside” the kodi chroot we just installed.</p>
<p>Enter the following command :</p>
<p>sudo apt-get install -y kodi</p>
<p>Once it is done, just exit the chroot by typing “ <strong>exit</strong> ” or hitting <strong>CTRL+D</strong> on you keyboard.</p>
<h2 id="and-thats-it-">And… that’s it !</h2>
<p>Now every time you want to run Kodi, open a Shell in Chrome by hitting <strong>CTRL+ALT+T</strong> and just type :</p>
<p>sudo enter-chroot -n kodi</p>
<p>then</p>
<p>startxfce4</p>
<p>Instead of those 2 commands, you would also directly try to only use:</p>
<p>sudo startxfce4</p>
<p>from the “shell” tab.</p>
<p>And it’ll run the XFCE dsktop in the “chroot” we just installed.</p>
<p>You can now run Kodi from the Menu inside the Multimedia category. I will say that is a pretty advanced tutorial, but if you have the “guts” to do it, then it’ll allow you to do huge things with a pretty cheap and decent piece of hardware that are Chrome OS.</p>
<p>This tutorial applies to any Chrome OS laptop and the beauty of having Linux on your Chrome OS is that you can do anything. This is a regular Kodi, in a regular Linux, no limitation at all.</p>
<p>I was afraid that Chrome OS would be pretty much locked down but actually once you activated that scary developer mode, you can do almost anything with ChromeOS, from installing Android apps, to Windows OS, and of course Linux.</p>
<p>NB : you can switch from/to ChromeOS and from/to Linux by hitting CTRL + ALT + SHIFT + Forward (or Backward). Forward and Backward are the keys on the right of the Esc key. You might have to press it a couple of times, for it to work.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>