<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>kodi emulator - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi-emulator/</link><description>kodi emulator - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 15:07:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi-emulator/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The original XBMC</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/the-original-xbmc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 15:07:32 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/the-original-xbmc/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/11/xbmc_xbox-300x200.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>This entry is part 1 of 1 in the series <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/series/retrogaming/" title="Retrogaming" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Retrogaming</a></p>
<p>Years ago, there was the original XBMC. Some of you might remember it, some others will discover it today.</p>
<h2 id="xbmc-history">XBMC history</h2>
<p>As you might already know, Kodi used to be called XBox Media Center. It used to be an homebrew (ie. a custom application) for the first Microsoft Xbox gaming console. Thanks to the Xbox hardware being very close to a regular PC and the fact it was “standardized” (ie. all xbox have the same hardware it quickly become a very powerful and famous software.</p>
<h2 id="xbmc-features">XBMC features</h2>
<p>XBMC allowed users to watch their movies (locally, or stored in network shares), listen to Music, check the weather, play “ripped” Xbox games, and various emulators. One feature, I would like to talk about was the ability to perform “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Retrogaming" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">retrogaming</a>“.</p>
<h2 id="xbmc-as-a-retrogaming-platform">XBMC as a retrogaming platform</h2>
<p>Nowadays, if one feel like playing old video console titles or arcade games in your living room, one can do so by installing an emulator on his computer and downloading some “roms” (<em>disclaimer : be sure to check your local laws before doing it</em>). However, playing old games on a regular PC is very often a lot of trouble: one must configure its controller for every emulator, tweak video and audio settings, etc. This is really a LOT of time wasted before begin able to play. This is where XBMC is great.</p>
<p>Since it has standardized hardware from audio, video chips to controller, it means that everyone using an Xbox uses the exact same setup (which will never be the case on a regular PC). In practical terms, it means that once the emulators are installed and the roms downloaded : everything is plug and play! No tweaking settings, no controller mappings, etc.</p>
<p>This was 13 years ago. Today, one can still play emulators on Kodi, however, since Kodi runs on a regular PC it is a lot more trouble… Unless we chose the road, once again to standardized hardware with Android device such as Nvidia Shield TV, or Raspberry Pis units.</p>
<h2 id="kodi-as-a-retrogaming-platform">Kodi as a retrogaming platform</h2>
<p>In a coming article, we’ll show you how to install Kodi on a regular PC and use it as a frontend for all your roms and emulators. I’ll also talk about great “out of the box” working distribution using Kodi and retrogaming apps. Stay tuned !</p>
<p>What’s about you : have you played the original Xbox? Did you use the original XBMC?</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>