<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>kodi xbmc - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi-xbmc/</link><description>kodi xbmc - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:05:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi-xbmc/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Nvidia Shield sucks?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:05:22 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/Nvidia-Shield-TV.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Yes, it is true. I think the Nvidia Shield sucks!
To be 4K or not to be First of, resolution ! I have plugged the shield on 3 different TV :
a 720p one ; a 1080p TV; a 4K TV. On the 720p TV, the Shield can only work at 1080p which means non native resolution and big visible pixels.
On the 1080p TV, the Shield will only work a 4K resolution with reduced refresh rate (24Hz)… which sucks cause you can spot the big pixels from your couch and refresh rate make it looks “slow” or laggy.</description></item><item><title>Kodi beginner's guide</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 10:58:20 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_beginner_guide.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>As a great alternative to popcorn time, I am going to share with you a nice Kodi beginner’s guide.
How to install Kodi Browse to official Kodi website, and download the version of your liking (ie. Windows or Mac OS). Click here in order to get directly there!
Here is a little video to help you :
Once Kodi is installed, it is time to set up the “appropriate” addons.</description></item><item><title>Kodi Genesis tips and tricks</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:00:52 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_genesis_tips.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Genesis is a great add-on that let’s you stream movies and TV Shows under Kodi, let me share with you some great Genesis tips and tricks.
Disclaimer : streaming movies and TV shows might be illegal in your country, be sure to comply with local laws.
Genesis Subtitles Did you know that you could enable automatic subtitles in Genesis? Yup! In order to do so, just navigate to the Video Add-ons &gt; Genesis &gt; Tools, this is the where Genesis is configured, and tweaked.]]></description></item><item><title>Kodi SuperRepo, enhance Kodi!</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-superrepo-enhance-kodi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 20:44:36 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-superrepo-enhance-kodi/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_superrepo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The SuperRepo will enhance Kodi, allowing you to add and keep up-to-date thousands of add-ons.
How to install SuperRepo on Kodi Go to Kodi Settings &gt; File manager :
Select Add source :
Enter the following URL, “http://SRP.nu” (without quotes) :
Once done, it should look like this (notice SRP as name of media source) :
Now go to Settings &gt; Add-ons :
Then choose Install from zip, browse to the SRP repo you just added until, you see something like below :]]></description></item><item><title>Is Kodi 4K ready?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/is-kodi-4k-ready/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 12:21:10 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/is-kodi-4k-ready/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_4k_rdy.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 1 of 1 in the series 4K
#4K display are becoming more and more affordable, but are they worth it? More importantly, what is really 4K and what are their pros and cons? And finally is #Kodi 4K ready? Let’s find out.
What is 4K? 4K is the “new resolution in town”. In order to understand 4K resolution, we have to understand what resolution is. According to Wikipedia, display resolution is “is the number of distinct pixels in each dimension that can be displayed”.</description></item><item><title>Popcorn time is dead... time to switch to Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead...-time-to-switch-to-kodi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 10:27:24 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead...-time-to-switch-to-kodi/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/10/rip.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Dear all,
#Popcorn Time has closed Sad news, Popcorn Time is dead. Popcorn Time was a great software, however due its P2P nature, it was not safe as I explained a few weeks ago which probably lead to its death. Fear not, there are alternatives, and the best one is right here on this site.
The Popcorn time alternative The alternative is #Kodi along with a good streaming plugin such as Genesis.</description></item><item><title>Popcorn Time is not safe, use Kodi as an alternative</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-not-safe-use-kodi-as-an-alternative/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 14:38:12 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-not-safe-use-kodi-as-an-alternative/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/popcorn.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>You have probably heard of Popcorn time. It is a great piece of software allowing you to stream Movies and TV Shows. However, #Popcorn Time is not safe, you should use #Kodi as an alternative. Here is why.
Kodi, thanks to some nifty plugins can allow you to stream movies and TV shows, just like Popcorn time. There is however one big difference.
Kodi streams its data directly from “established” websites, this is what we call “direct download” or direct streaming.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 4 : OpenElec</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-4-openelec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 07:34:47 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-4-openelec/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>This entry is part 4 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
Last but not least, we’ll explain you how to install #OpenElec on your Pi!
Prepare before install Mandatory  Raspberry #Pi 2 Micro SD Card (&gt;512MB) Power Adapter (&gt;=1A) Micro USB Cable  Optional  Keyboard Mouse Remote WLAN Dongle Ethernet Cable Case  Steps  Download the ARMv7 Stable build from official site ; Extract it and navigate to extracted files and folder ; If using Linux or Mac Os, just run “create_sdcard” file, follow instructions and go to “Install OpenElec” part ; If using Windows, download win32diskimager and run it ; Select image file you just downloaded and point it to your SD card.]]></description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 3 : media center</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-3-media-center/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 07:34:41 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-3-media-center/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 3 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
Today we’ll talk about media center solutions for the Pis. Let’s go!
Media Center Distribution One of the most common use of the Raspberry #Pi 2 is to build a media center out of it. In order to so, one have access to several different “tools”. Let’s do a quick presentation.
#Raspbian This is a Linux, Debian based OS (aka distribution).</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 2 : different uses</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-2-different-uses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 06:04:51 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-2-different-uses/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 2 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
In the first part, we saw a brief presentation of the #Pi 2 hardware with some pictures. Now, in the sequel, we’ll see what you can do with a #Raspberry Pi 2.
Hardware applications You could build a Temperature and Humidity Sensor, in order to monitor room temperature or help you grow vegetables thanks to the readings.
If you are the gaming type, you could always build an Arcade Pi.</description></item></channel></rss>