<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>istream - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/istream/</link><description>istream - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:48:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/istream/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Streaming on Kodi : iStream vs Genesis</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/streaming-on-kodi-istream-vs-genesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:48:04 +0200</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/streaming-on-kodi-istream-vs-genesis/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/05/Genesis_vs_istream.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>It has been a long time without posting. Today, I am back, and I hope I’ll be able to keep this website updated.</p>
<p>Lately, I have totally changed my way of watching media. For years, I used to get my media from newsgroups and store them and my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00EN1BZL0?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=6738&amp;tag=kodi-xbmc-20&amp;creativeASIN=B00EN1BZL0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">custom built NAS</a>. Since I discovered streaming plugins, I no longer store media, so that I can focus on backing up my data from my several computers to the NAS.</p>
<p>I found that, in same the same way “there is an app for this”, there is a plugin for each case.</p>
<h3 id="streaming-old-tv-shows">Streaming old TV Shows</h3>
<p>By old I mean no longer running TV Shows, or first seasons of a long run TV Show (eg: The Simpsons). When I want to stream this kind of media, I’ll go with <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-stream-tv-shows-and-movies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">genesis</a>. It is fast, has many feeds, and good working search funtion that, most of the time, directly find what I am looking for. Whereas, <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/istream/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#istream</a> will return many, many results, and the right one is often lost in the middle of non relevant answers.</p>
<h3 id="streaming-running-tv-shows">Streaming running TV Shows</h3>
<p>When you are downloading media with soft like sabnzbd, or nzbget, you get notified in <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#kodi</a> / <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/xbmc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#xbmc</a> when a new file has been added. Everything is automated, and it is great (to be lazy). Now, with the streaming, you no longer have the notification when a new show is available for streaming, unless you subscribe to different services in order to “track” shows.</p>
<p>However, thanks to <a href="http://xunitytalk.com/forum.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iStream</a> and the subscription function (I’ll add an article about this later on) you can now keep track of all the new TV shows as soon as they become available. Definately a must have!</p>
<h3 id="streaming-movies">Streaming Movies</h3>
<p>On the movie side, I hate screeners, and I don’t keep myself updated about latest and/or popular movies. I rearely watch movies, and I decide to do so, I just want to watch some cover and select one from the cover and/or title.</p>
<p>For this kind if watching, I am using <a href="http://xunitytalk.com/forum.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iStream</a> as well. It has a great function, that allows me to find movies based of Box Office by years. This means, that I’ll never select the “latest” or current year movies in order to avoid ugly screeners.</p>
<p>This way, I have good quality movies and at the same time “popular” movies. Perfect for me!</p>
<p>I hope, it will help you slack in front of “TV”.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>When morons steal IStream's code</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/when-morons-steal-istreams-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 10:48:56 +0200</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/when-morons-steal-istreams-code/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/04/iStream.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Today, while setting up my Twitter account, I learned about a new <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#kodi</a> Add-on called <a href="http://www.xunitytalk.com/forum.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">istream from Xunitytalk</a>. I will probably write about soon, when I have played with it long enough.</p>
<p>However what I also learned today was far more troublesome. <strong>Some people, stole the great work from <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/istream/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#IStream</a></strong> in order to make a new plugin from it. I don’t want to give them any credit, but I feel obliged to name them : <strong>AAA Stream</strong>.</p>
<p>if you are using it, just know they stole the original source code and are potentially making money out of someone else’s work. <strong>Do what you feel right</strong> , ie: uninstall their plugin, talk about it, do nothing, etc.</p>
<p>As you can see <strong>I felt right to share the word</strong> , and I really hope noone will use “their” add-on.</p>
<p>This is my really small contribution and I hope it will help.</p>
<p>For more information, you can find iStream official’s dev Twitter here : <a href="https://twitter.com/Mikey1234_XBMC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://twitter.com/Mikey1234_XBMC</a></p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>