<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>windows - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/windows/</link><description>windows - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 14:03:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/windows/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automagically deploy apps with GPO and Boxstarter</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 14:03:32 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/boxstarter.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>A few days ago, I talked about <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Ninite, which is an awesome tool to deploy several Windows apps easily</a>. However, if you want to use it on a Windows domain (likely in your company), you&rsquo;ll have to get the Pro (and paid version). Hopefully, with BoxStarter, you can do it for free. Let me show you how I do it.</p>
<h2 id="lets-do-some-scripting">Let&rsquo;s do some scripting!</h2>
<p>In my case, I want all my users to have the same &ldquo;base apps&rdquo; installed on their systems. It allows my team and I to make sure every user has access to some &ldquo;must-have&rdquo; apps like :</p>
<ul>
<li>remote access client for support ;</li>
<li>a good text editor ;</li>
<li>some video player ;</li>
<li>etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, I want to automate this. No worry, I&rsquo;ll share a little PowerShell script, but thanks to BoxStarter, it will be VERY easy.</p>
<p>We no further ado, here is the script :</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">### Determine which version of PowerShell is running if ($PSVersionTable.PSversion.Major -eq &#34;2&#34;) ## PowerShell V2 { iex ((New-Object System.Net.WebClient).DownloadString(&#39;https://boxstarter.org/bootstrapper.ps1&#39;)); get-boxstarter -Force } else ## PowerShell V3 { . { iwr -useb http://boxstarter.org/bootstrapper.ps1 } | iex; get-boxstarter -Force } ## List of apps to be installed $apps = &#34;Firefox&#34;, &#34;teamviewer.portable&#34;, &#34;glaryutilities-free&#34;, &#34;vlc&#34;, &#34;windirstat&#34;, &#34;pidgin&#34;, &#34;7zip&#34;, &#34;notepadplusplus&#34; foreach($app in $apps) { cinst -y $app }
</code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div><p>Let me explain a little bit what it does.</p>
<p>Since BoxStarter needs a different command line to be installed depending of the version of PowerShell, we must first determine if we are running PowerShell V3 (Windows 8 to Windows 10), or PowerShell V2 (Windows 7).</p>
<p>Once we found out which version is running, we install the base &ldquo;framework' for BoxStarter, called BoxStarter Shell.</p>
<p>Finally, we simply declare a list of apps, in which we write the name of all the apps we want to install.</p>
<p>NB: BoxStarter is based on Chocolatey and <a href="https://chocolatey.org/packages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">all the available packages (= apps) can be found here</a>, or via the command &ldquo;choco search package&rdquo; (once the BoxStarter shell is installed).</p>
<p>Please also note that BoxStarter also allow you to modify Windows settings, such as &ldquo;Show hidden files&rdquo;, &ldquo;Acitvate remote desktop&rdquo;, etc.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-make-sure-every-user-get-the-script">How to make sure every user get the script?</h2>
<p>The way I distribute those apps is via a GPO defined on the AD server. This is a user based GPO, and it executes itself at session&rsquo;s start.</p>
<p>Which means, you have to create it into : User configuration &gt; Windows settings &gt; Scripts (session start).</p>
<p>From here, make sure to use the 2nd tab on the top in order to use a PowerShell script.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Then click &ldquo;Add&rdquo;, and &ldquo;Open directory' and you&rsquo;ll be brought up to the folder dedicated to this particular GPO :</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">%SystemRoot%SYSVOLsysvol&lt;domain DNS name&gt;Policies{GUID}ComputerScriptsStartup
</code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div><p>Just paste your script inside this directory, and select it.</p>
<p>Now, in the &ldquo;Parameters&rdquo; field, make sure to add the following line :</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">-ExecutionPolicy Bypass
</code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div><p>This line ensures, the script will be run whatever <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/module/microsoft.powershell.core/about/about_execution_policies?view=powershell-6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">execution policy</a> is in place.</p>
<p>From now on, any user that this GPO applies to will get the apps installed (if not already) and frequently updated.</p>
<p>NB: The very first run can take a little time and resources (in the background), but it should be barely noticeable.</p>
<h2 id="a-note-of-caution">A note of caution</h2>
<p>With any GPO work, care is the word ! This is why I advise you to test, test, test&hellip; before putting it into production.</p>
<p>In order to do so, you can create &ldquo;fake&rdquo; users and apply that GPO only to those users. You can also create a Testing OU in which you&rsquo;ll put, for example, the IT team, etc.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Install Windows programs like a boss with Ninite</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 23:36:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/ninite.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Do you remember how you used to install programs under Windows several years ago? Next, next, next&hellip; Are you still doing it the exact same way today? If that&rsquo;s so, I may have something of interest for you, keep reading !</p>
<h2 id="windows-programs-installation-is-so-painful">Windows' programs' installation is so painful</h2>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I am quite pissed off with the way &ldquo;software&rdquo; works on Windows. Let&rsquo;s say you want to install <a href="https://www.videolan.org/vlc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">VLC</a> to watch movies, then you have to fire up your web browser, go to VLC website (probably via a search engine), find the correct version (32 or 64 bits), download the product, and install it. Rinse and repeat in order to keep your software updated&hellip;</p>
<h2 id="the-linux-way">The Linux way</h2>
<p>In order to give an element of comparison, installing a program under Linux is totally different, and more user friendly. You have to fire up your &ldquo;<a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/UbuntuSoftwareCenter?action=show&amp;redirect=SoftwareCenterFAQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">software manager program</a>&rdquo;, search for VLC, and click install! That&rsquo;s it, VLC will be automatically installed with the most appropriate version (32 or 64 bits), concerning the updates, no need to think about them : your operating system will update it automagically on a regular basis (think of a working Windows update tool that also includes updates for any program that is installed on your system, like VLC or Steam). This is very similar to the way your phone works !</p>
<p>The way Linux manages installation of software is done via &ldquo;repositories&rdquo;. It is some kind of huge catalog that holds several software in the same &ldquo;place&rdquo; and keep them updated. From the user perspective, everything is &ldquo;centralized&rdquo; : it means the user can manage all its software needs in one place. However, have in mind, that on the &ldquo;developer&rdquo; or &ldquo;system&rdquo; side, this is not centralized at all. There are several copies of every software all around the world! Just in case a location &ldquo;fails&rdquo;, there will be another one available&hellip; or just a closer location to the final user in order to reduce download times.</p>
<h2 id="please-welcome-ninite">Please welcome Ninite</h2>
<p>Some smart people (a lot smarter than me!) have decided to create similar systems for Windows. Such systems are called <a href="https://chocolatey.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Chocolatey</a>, or Ninite. While Chocolatey can be more intimidating, Ninite is very easy to use.</p>
<p><a href="https://ninite.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Just browse to their official website</a>, and simply check the boxes corresponding to the programs you want to install on your system. Once you are done &ldquo;free shopping&rdquo;, just hit the &ldquo;Get your Ninite&rdquo; button at the bottom of the page. This should automatically download a very small file.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now, you just have to run the aforementioned file from your computer, and it&rsquo;ll try to install every software you &ldquo;included&rdquo; in it:</p>
<ul>
<li>If the program is already installed, and up to date, it will try to install the next one ;</li>
<li>if the program is already installed but not up to date, it&rsquo;ll download the latest version and update it ;</li>
<li>If the program is not installed, it will download and install it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Finally, if you need to update your programs, let&rsquo;s say a few weeks after the initial install, just run the Ninite installer once again. You could also set up a scheduled task to automatically run the Ninite updater once in a while. This is however, not perfect since, the Ninite installer will &ldquo;pop up&rdquo; on your screen&hellip; only the Pro version as a &ldquo;silent&rdquo; mode that runs in the background without bugging you.</p>
<h2 id="last-but-not-least">Last but not least&hellip;</h2>
<p>Ninite &ldquo;classic&rdquo; (as compared to Pro version, with silent installer for example) is totally free.</p>
<p>It only contains &ldquo;approved&rdquo; apps : which means those apps come without any spyware / adware or any additional unwanted software. Remember when you installed Avast and it automatically checks a box to install Google Chrome as well? It won&rsquo;t happen here!</p>
<p>Finally, Ninite is compatible with every version of Windows (from XP to 10), and the corresponding &ldquo;server&rdquo; version.</p>
<p>If you are still reading this article, I believe you are not using Windows&hellip; or you are already using Ninite. <a href="https://ninite.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Come on, go manage your preferred app in a clever way, now</a>!</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Sending text messages from your computer</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 11:12:57 +0200</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/send_text_from_pc.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Do you hate touchscreen? I sure do! More than touchscreen, I hate when I have to write something using a touch screen. This is why, I have been trying and using different solutions that allows me to send text messages from my computer with a real (mechanical) keyboard!</p>
<h2 id="foreword">Foreword</h2>
<p>Please note that this guide is based on Android phones and is desktop &ldquo;OS&rdquo; agnostic.</p>
<p>If you are using Apple phones and computers, then <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202549" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">have a look here</a>.</p>
<p>Under Windows Phone, check what <a href="https://pureinfotech.com/how-send-sms-texts-using-cortana-windows-10-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Cortana can do for you</a>.</p>
<p>However, some apps I am talking about are also probably working on Apple and/or Windows phones. Be sure to check your app store!</p>
<h2 id="mightytext">MightyText</h2>
<p><a href="https://mightytext.net/install" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MightyText</a> is a free app that can be downloaded via the Play Store. The setup is straightforward: it will &ldquo;only&rdquo; ask you to give access to your Google account from the phone, and the same thing on your computer. So that both your devices all linked together thanks to this common account.</p>
<p>On your computer, MightyText can be accessed from various ways :</p>
<ul>
<li>From a webpage : meaning it will run on any computer that can run a web browser ;</li>
<li>There is also a desktop client for Macos and Windows, but not for Linux ;</li>
<li>You can also use an extension for the Chrome browser, but not from Firefox.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, in my opinion it is best to have the MightyText app always running on your desktop, so that you don&rsquo;t miss any text / notification and can reply asap. Which means, depending on your OS and browser of choice, you might have limited options. Let&rsquo;s say for example, you are running Linux and using Firefox, then your only choice will be to leave a Firefox tab always open&hellip; This might not be a problem for most people, but I personally hate to have too many tabs open&hellip; This, and only this, is a no go for me.</p>
<p>As you might have noticed, I also talked about receiving notifications on your computer. Indeed, with this kind of apps, you can also do that. Again, it can be very useful if like me you are only using webmail and don&rsquo;t want to leave an extra tab and/or app open in the background to receive new email notifications.</p>
<p>Thanks to MightyText, you&rsquo;ll receive a destop notification when you receive an email on your phone, then you just have to browse to your webmail, and take action.</p>
<p>Supposedly, you are able to filter which apps from your phone are allowed to send notifications all the way up to your desktop. However I couldn&rsquo;t find how to do that, and it means a lot of spam on my desktop. Especially when I was using Telegram on the desktop to chat, I was receiving notifications from both the Desktop client and the mobile client through the MightText app! Another no go&hellip;</p>
<p>EDIT 22/09/2017: Thanks to their support on Twitter, this is how we filter apps notifications:<br>
Yes, you can customize this by visiting the MightyText web app &ndash; Phone tab &ndash; Apps section. Let us know if that works for you.</p>
<p>This led me to check another well known player: Pushbullet.</p>
<h2 id="pushbullet">Pushbullet</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.pushbullet.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Pushbullet</a> configuration works almost the same way than MightyText does. You need to give access to your Google account to all devices that you want to be linked together. However, it supports both Google and Facebook accounts, while MightyText only supports Google accounts.</p>
<p>Once again, when the app is installed on your mobile phone, you can access it from your desktop as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>From a webpage : meaning it will run on any computer that can run a web browser ;</li>
<li>There is also a desktop client for Windows.. and just Windows ;</li>
<li>You can also use an extension for the main browsers: Chrome, Firefox, Opera, Safari.</li>
</ul>
<p>In my opinion, this is much better than the other app mentioned before as it gives you a lot more possibilities. Like I said before, thanks to the browser extensions, you now have the app running and listening to incoming messages and notifications all the time your browser is open and without having to waste a tab. It is even foolproof, you won&rsquo;t forget to open the tab!</p>
<p>Here again, we can choose to filter notifications, and this time, I found it pretty straightforward to set it up. Which means no spamming on my desktop, and only receiving the desired notifications. I&rsquo;ll get notifications for emails, appointments and of course text messages, which of course I can reply to with my keyboard.</p>
<h2 id="but-what-about-sending-messages">But what about sending messages?</h2>
<p>This is the main usage for these two apps, and it works well&hellip; most of the time!</p>
<p>About 95% of the time, it &ldquo;just works&rdquo;. You receive a desktop notification about a new text. Just click on it, it will open the message and you can directly reply to it. Contact names appears the same way they would on your phone. If you want to create a new message, just select your contact&rsquo;s name inside the browser extension (for example) to write your text. Send, it! Done.</p>
<p>Then, 5% of the time&hellip; the message will stay &ldquo;stuck&rdquo; on your computer and won&rsquo;t be relayed to you phone, hence they won&rsquo;t be sent. At the time of writing, it only happened to me when I killed the app on phone (beware with the &ldquo;kill all&rdquo; function of Android phones). In those case, I just started the app again on the phone, and it fixed it.<br>
There could also be issues with battery management where the phone puts the app to sleep in order to reduce battery usage. If you have issues about not being able to send SMS after some time, then <a href="http://www.techrepublic.com/article/how-to-remove-android-apps-from-the-battery-optimization-list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">make sure that Android no longer optimize the battery</a> for this app.</p>
<p>Last but not least, all the messages sent / received from the computer will continue to appear in your default messages app, just like if you sent them from the phone.</p>
<h2 id="closing-words-and-a-few-other-alternatives">Closing words and a few other alternatives</h2>
<p>As we have seen those apps can be very handy, especially if you hate using touchscreen. It is also a good way to synchronize your phone and computer and remove extra app on the desktop, close a few browser tabs, etc.</p>
<p>In my opinion, the fact that Pushbullet offers browser extensions for all the major browsers is a great plus! Moreover, I feel it easier to navigate in the app, find what you are looking for, and tweak it (ie. the notification thingy). In a few words, we could say that Pushbullet is more basic, maybe even less &ldquo;bloated&rdquo;. Like I didn&rsquo;t see any ads in Pushbullet, while I see some using MightyText webpage.</p>
<p>Now, if you want to follow that road but feel to restricted by those 2 apps, you can also have a look a few other alternatives such as <a href="https://joaoapps.com/join-sms-from-anything-with-a-browser/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Join</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.klinker.messenger&amp;hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Pulse</a>. They look like pretty strong competitors as well.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this article and that it might have helped you. Better yet, given you faith again in your texting business!</p>
<p>Do not hesitate to let me know if you use any other similar app, most especially if you love it.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Microsoft let you down, Windows Easy Transfer is dead</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/microsoft-let-you-down-windows-easy-transfer-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:43:07 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/microsoft-let-you-down-windows-easy-transfer-is-dead/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/easy_trasnfer_is_dead.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Christmas is just over, you bought a fresh new computer and planned to run Windows Easy Transfer in order to move your data to the new computer? Plan again! Wndows Easy Transfer is dead and will not help you! Hopefully if you are here, unlike Microsoft I will help you.</p>
<h2 id="the-good-old-windows-easy-transfer">The good old Windows Easy Transfer</h2>
<p>Until Windows 8.1, transfering files from an old Windows computer to a new one, was an easy process. All you had to do was fire up the official Microsoft Tool called Windows Easy Transfer (aka <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Easy_Transfer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">WET</a>). I am a Linux user, but I used this tool several times in order to move data for friends and familly, I am the familly geek. The one that gets call every now and then when something computerish (I insist on the ish) doesn’t work as expected.</p>
<h2 id="microsoft-killed-it">Microsoft killed it!</h2>
<p>However, I have been surprised to discover, only a few days ago, that this tool no longer exists in Wndows 10. Microsoft replaced it with <a href="http://www.laplink.com/index.php/fre/individuals/pcmover-for-windows/pcmover-express" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Laplink PC Mover Express</a>. The not so funny part is that this tool is NOT free (not free, as yes you have to pay for it even you already paid an expensive Windows licence).</p>
<p>Supposedly there was a free version during the first months of Windows 10, but it is no longer the case. Which means if you happen to buy a new computer and decide to move old files from the old one to the new one, then you’ll have no official / free / included solution available. That is a shame Mr. Microsoft!</p>
<h2 id="alternatives-to-windows-easy-transfer">Alternatives to Windows Easy Transfer</h2>
<p>Luckily enough for us, many other software editor decided to go down that road and are now offering similar software. Most of them are paid software but some of them are free.</p>
<p>It is important to note / know, that it is very highly recommended to keep the same username on the old and new computer.</p>
<h3 id="easeus-todo-pctrans">EaseUS TODO PCTrans</h3>
<p>This is my favorite tool. I might be biased, because I already use their partition manager software.</p>
<p>Installation is fine and the software doesn’t try to install any additional crapeware like toolbars, or to make you switch to some other browser… This is much appreciated.</p>
<p>Once the program is installed on both computer, you can run it.</p>
<p>The program itself is pretty straightforward and do what’s needed take a backup of your files (and up to only 2 applications) on the old computer. Then you can restore this backup on the new computer.</p>
<p>Backup/restore can be done via external disks (faster and prefered method), or directlty by the network (from old computer to new computer).</p>
<p>I highly recommend to use the free version in order to backup your user directory located at :</p>
<p>C:UsersYourUsername</p>
<p>NB : change your username</p>
<p>Then, for applications, just use a tool like NInite to install as many as possible applications possible. If some of your applications are not available on NInite, you can add up to 2 applications with EaseUS TODO PCTrans. For the rest install them “manually”.</p>
<p>Please note that data related to applications is located in the folder you have just backuped. That’s to say, if you are using Firefox, then as soon as you install Firefox (even if you install it manually), it will look for its data inside the above folder  and your session will be automagically restored with all your extension, browsing history, etc.</p>
<h3 id="manual-way">Manual way</h3>
<p>This is another good method. More advanced, but one that will works everywhere, everytime. But also one that requires a bit more work and hardware. Let’s call it the expert’s way.</p>
<p>For this method, you need to download any Linux Live CD. For example, go for Ubuntu as it is the most common one.</p>
<ul>
<li>Burn it to a DVD or make an USB bootable key.</li>
<li>Boot the Live disk/key on the old computer.</li>
<li>Once it has completely booted, you should be brought to a desktop, like the Windows desktop.</li>
<li>Plug-in an external hard drive (the drive must have enough space to store the data you want to transfer).</li>
<li>From here, there should be several icons on your desktop. We are particularly interested about 2 of them. The first one being the one for your WIndows disk and the second one being the one from the exterdan hard drive you have just plugged.</li>
<li>Once, you figure out which is what. You just have to browse your old “Windows” disk and find the folder corresponding to your user. It should end like this:</li>
</ul>
<p>Users/YouUsername</p>
<p>NB: make sure to change accordingly to your real username</p>
<ul>
<li>Once you have found this folder, right click on it and click Copy.</li>
<li>Then, just like you would do with WIndows, browse to the external disk and right click on some blank space and click Paste.</li>
<li>Once the copy is over. Shut off the computer, plug the bootable disk/key to the new computer.</li>
<li>Proceed like before, but this time you’ll copy the data FROM the external disk TO the new Windows disk.</li>
<li>Once copy is over, shutdown computer, unplug key/disks.</li>
</ul>
<p>Then you can normally turn on computer, and install missing apps with Ninite. Don’t worry about app configuration, it will come back the same way it was on the old computer as soon as you run them.</p>
<p>That’s it, you can now easily transfer your files from Windows 10 computer without the without Easy Transfer tool. If you wish to learn more about the Linux method, I can share with you my “real” method, based on command lines.</p>
<p>Just drop me a comment!</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Windows Store Apps suck</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/windows-store-apps-suck/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 15:02:43 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/windows-store-apps-suck/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2017/01/321663584_19f1fcdfba_o.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Remember the good old times, when you could simply install any program wherever you pleased on your computer and just click an “exe” file to run it? Well, this is time over thanks to Microsoft, and Windows Store Apps suck!</p>
<h2 id="let-me-introduce-you">Let me introduce you…</h2>
<p>The Windows Store! Since Windows 8, Microsoft has released the Windows, and it keeps pushing it through the front door. On the gaming front, it is even <a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/tim-sweeney-says-microsoft-will-break-steam-and-force-you-to-use-the-windows-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">trying to kill Steam</a>. However, it is  far far worse than Steam. Both are proprietary which kind of suck but in Steam, at least, you can configure some basic stuff. In Microsoft Store, you can’t really do that.. and this is why Windows Store Apps suck.</p>
<h2 id="windows-store-apps-suck">Windows Store Apps suck</h2>
<p>I just bought Forza Horizon 3 on the Windows Store, and wanted to “simply” add it my Steam library. Once again, I couldn’t be more wrong. This was way harder than expected.</p>
<h3 id="lets-see-for-now-how-the-2-apps-compares-">Let’s see for now how the 2 apps compares :</h3>
<p>Both apps are “store” like applications. Which means you have a “main” application in which you can buy other apps/games. Those games/apps are then usually run from the Store or directly from a shortcut.</p>
<h4 id="location-of-bought-apps">Location of bought apps</h4>
<ul>
<li>In Steam, you can simply <a href="https://support.steampowered.com/kb_article.php?ref=7418-YUBN-8129" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">change the “library” folder from the Steam GUI</a>. Which is very useful, if you wan to store all your games on a separate drive.</li>
<li>In Windows Store, well, you have to run <a href="http://www.thewindowsclub.com/change-default-install-location-windows-8-store-apps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">regedit</a>…</li>
</ul>
<p>Windows Store apps suck… bit time for this!</p>
<h4 id="an-app-is-an-app">An app is an app</h4>
<p>An app is an app, which means some files / folders, and an executable file to run the said app.</p>
<ul>
<li>With Steam, it is!</li>
<li>With Windows Store, it isn’t! MS has decided to go with some package thingy. You have a package folder but no executable file at all! It is launching it by running some kind of environment variable stuff. And yeah, this is very complicated stuff for a particularly ridiculously easy task.</li>
</ul>
<p>Windows Store apps suck… they really do!</p>
<h2 id="but-i-can-still-add-them-on-steam-right">But I can still add them on Steam right?</h2>
<p>Of course, if you want to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Steam/comments/3vgrcu/adding_windows_store_apps_to_steam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">add a Windows Store game to Steam</a>, you can still do it. However, it’ll be painful. More importantly, if you decided, like me to run <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/turn-computer-gaming-console/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Steam in shell mode</a>, then you’ll not be able to run those Windows Store Apps from Steam…</p>
<p>If you followed the guide to add Windows Store game to Steam, you have probably noticed that the way we run a Windows Store app from Steam is that we run the explorer (from Windows) command and add it the path to the Windows Store package as argument. However, strangely enough, for this to work, then explorer.exe must already be running! Really, I’ll never get you Microsoft…</p>
<p>I haven’t said it enough, Windows Store Apps suck, don’t buy them!</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Install Kodi on Windows 10</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 08:41:01 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-windows-10/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/install_kodi_win_10.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>The new Windows is here, please follow our latest video in order to install Kodi on Windows 10.</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vKzOYtXu7L4?feature=oembed" width="200"></iframe>
<h2 id="install-kodi-on-windows-10">Install Kodi on Windows 10</h2>
<p>This is pretty easy, as usual follow these few steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Go to <a href="http://kodi.tv/download/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">kodi.tv Downloads page</a>;</li>
<li>Download the required version;</li>
<li>Install it by clicking “Next”;</li>
<li>Run and enjoy!</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="or-else">Or else…</h2>
<p>You could also check our <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Kodi Beginner’s Guide</a> for more detailed and advanced setup.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>How to Install Kodi in Windows</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-install-kodi-in-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:53:20 +0200</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-install-kodi-in-windows/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/install_kodi_windows.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>During this short video, I’ll show you <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/how-to/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#how to</a> install <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#kodi</a> (formerly know as <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/xbmc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#xbmc</a>).</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="150" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rcbHV9ErRzk?feature=oembed" width="200"></iframe>
<p>It is a simple 2 steps process :</p>
<ol>
<li>downloading the software ;</li>
<li>installing it.</li>
</ol>
<p>First, fire up your favorite browser and naivgate to <a href="http://kodi.tv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">kodi.tv</a>, click on the Downloads link and select the Windows version.</p>
<p>Wait for download to finish.</p>
<p>Then, run the installer and just click “Next” until the installation is complete.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>