<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>windows - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/windows/</link><description>windows - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022 Masoopy.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 14:03:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/windows/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automagically deploy apps with GPO and Boxstarter</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 14:03:32 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/boxstarter.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A few days ago, I talked about Ninite, which is an awesome tool to deploy several Windows apps easily. However, if you want to use it on a Windows domain (likely in your company), you&rsquo;ll have to get the Pro (and paid version). Hopefully, with BoxStarter, you can do it for free. Let me show you how I do it.
Let&rsquo;s do some scripting! In my case, I want all my users to have the same &ldquo;base apps&rdquo; installed on their systems.]]></description></item><item><title>Install Windows programs like a boss with Ninite</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 23:36:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/ninite.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Do you remember how you used to install programs under Windows several years ago? Next, next, next&hellip; Are you still doing it the exact same way today? If that&rsquo;s so, I may have something of interest for you, keep reading !
Windows' programs' installation is so painful I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I am quite pissed off with the way &ldquo;software&rdquo; works on Windows. Let&rsquo;s say you want to install VLC to watch movies, then you have to fire up your web browser, go to VLC website (probably via a search engine), find the correct version (32 or 64 bits), download the product, and install it.]]></description></item><item><title>Sending text messages from your computer</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 11:12:57 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/send_text_from_pc.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Do you hate touchscreen? I sure do! More than touchscreen, I hate when I have to write something using a touch screen. This is why, I have been trying and using different solutions that allows me to send text messages from my computer with a real (mechanical) keyboard!
Foreword Please note that this guide is based on Android phones and is desktop &ldquo;OS&rdquo; agnostic.
If you are using Apple phones and computers, then have a look here.]]></description></item><item><title>Microsoft let you down, Windows Easy Transfer is dead</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/microsoft-let-you-down-windows-easy-transfer-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:43:07 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/microsoft-let-you-down-windows-easy-transfer-is-dead/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/easy_trasnfer_is_dead.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Christmas is just over, you bought a fresh new computer and planned to run Windows Easy Transfer in order to move your data to the new computer? Plan again! Wndows Easy Transfer is dead and will not help you! Hopefully if you are here, unlike Microsoft I will help you.
The good old Windows Easy Transfer Until Windows 8.1, transfering files from an old Windows computer to a new one, was an easy process.</description></item><item><title>Windows Store Apps suck</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/windows-store-apps-suck/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 15:02:43 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/windows-store-apps-suck/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2017/01/321663584_19f1fcdfba_o.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Remember the good old times, when you could simply install any program wherever you pleased on your computer and just click an “exe” file to run it? Well, this is time over thanks to Microsoft, and Windows Store Apps suck!
Let me introduce you… The Windows Store! Since Windows 8, Microsoft has released the Windows, and it keeps pushing it through the front door. On the gaming front, it is even trying to kill Steam.</description></item><item><title>Install Kodi on Windows 10</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 08:41:01 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-windows-10/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/install_kodi_win_10.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>The new Windows is here, please follow our latest video in order to install Kodi on Windows 10.
Install Kodi on Windows 10 This is pretty easy, as usual follow these few steps:
Go to kodi.tv Downloads page; Download the required version; Install it by clicking “Next”; Run and enjoy! Or else… You could also check our Kodi Beginner’s Guide for more detailed and advanced setup.</description></item><item><title>How to Install Kodi in Windows</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-install-kodi-in-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:53:20 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-install-kodi-in-windows/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/install_kodi_windows.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>During this short video, I’ll show you #how to install #kodi (formerly know as #xbmc).
It is a simple 2 steps process :
downloading the software ; installing it. First, fire up your favorite browser and naivgate to kodi.tv, click on the Downloads link and select the Windows version.
Wait for download to finish.
Then, run the installer and just click “Next” until the installation is complete.</description></item></channel></rss>