<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>automation - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/automation/</link><description>automation - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022 Masoopy.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 08:48:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/automation/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manage VMware snapshots with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/manage-vmware-snapshots-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 08:48:46 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/manage-vmware-snapshots-with-powercli/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2018/12/Manage-VMware-snapshots-with-PowerCLI.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Manually taking a snapshot under VMware is easy : connect to the HTML5 Web UI, find the server from the list, right click, select Snapshot, Name it&hellip; However, when you have to do it several times in a row, it becomes really frustrating. Let&rsquo;s see how to improve that.
Here comes PowerCLI VMware released an awesome (and I am Linux guy) tool to manage your virtual machines from the command line.]]></description></item><item><title>Automagically deploy apps with GPO and Boxstarter</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 14:03:32 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automagically-deploy-apps-with-gpo-and-boxstarter/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/boxstarter.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A few days ago, I talked about Ninite, which is an awesome tool to deploy several Windows apps easily. However, if you want to use it on a Windows domain (likely in your company), you&rsquo;ll have to get the Pro (and paid version). Hopefully, with BoxStarter, you can do it for free. Let me show you how I do it.
Let&rsquo;s do some scripting! In my case, I want all my users to have the same &ldquo;base apps&rdquo; installed on their systems.]]></description></item><item><title>Install Windows programs like a boss with Ninite</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 23:36:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-windows-programs-like-a-boss-with-ninite/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/ninite.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Do you remember how you used to install programs under Windows several years ago? Next, next, next&hellip; Are you still doing it the exact same way today? If that&rsquo;s so, I may have something of interest for you, keep reading !
Windows' programs' installation is so painful I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I am quite pissed off with the way &ldquo;software&rdquo; works on Windows. Let&rsquo;s say you want to install VLC to watch movies, then you have to fire up your web browser, go to VLC website (probably via a search engine), find the correct version (32 or 64 bits), download the product, and install it.]]></description></item></channel></rss>