<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>kodi - Balise - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi/</link><description>kodi - Balise - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 16:04:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back to the sources : Kodi on Xbox One</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/back-to-the-sources-kodi-on-xbox-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 16:04:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/back-to-the-sources-kodi-on-xbox-one/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/xbone.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Almost 15 years ago, XBMC was created. Like today, it was a media center allowing you to watch your media, listen to your music and even playing old school games and Xbox games. All of this on place, and all of this on one specific hardware : the first generation Microsoft Xbox.
A new era Then the Xbox 360 has been released but Kodi was never part of it. In 2013, the latest and curren gen Xbox, the One was released.</description></item><item><title>Install Kodi on your Chromebook with Android</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-your-chromebook-with-android/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:15:26 +0200</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-your-chromebook-with-android/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2016/04/Chromebook.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A few days ago, I wrote a new guide in order to show you a new, easier and more reliable method to install Kodi on any Chromebook using crouton. Now, if you are lucky, your Chromebook might be elligible to install the Android Play Store&hellip; Let&rsquo;s see if that&rsquo;s is the case and if it is, we will see how to install Kodi using the Android Play Store on your Chromebook.]]></description></item><item><title>Directly Install Kodi on your Chromebook</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/directly-install-kodi-on-your-chromebook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 13:56:38 +0200</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/directly-install-kodi-on-your-chromebook/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2016/04/Chromebook.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Thanks to Zach, we now have a great way to install Kodi on our Chromebook.
Switch your Chromebook to developper&rsquo;s mode In order to install Kodi on Chrome OS, we’ll need to install a proper Linux system. Don’t worry, this is done easily thanks to the crouton script.
NB : be aware that turning developer’s mode ON, will delete ALL your data on the device!
First of all you have to turn on the developer’s mode on your device.]]></description></item><item><title>Automatically run Kodi at boot</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automatically-run-kodi-at-boot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 09:49:06 +0200</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automatically-run-kodi-at-boot/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>You have some hardware dedicated to Kodi and wish to create a “clean” media center solution hooked to your TV? Great idea! Find out how to automatically run Kodi at boot on any platform.
Automatically run Kodi at boot with Windows This method is similar to the Steam Shell mode.. but with Kodi.
First of all, make sure you can can log into the Windows desktop automatically. In order to do so:</description></item><item><title>Why Nvidia Shield sucks?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:05:22 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/Nvidia-Shield-TV.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Yes, it is true. I think the Nvidia Shield sucks!
To be 4K or not to be First of, resolution ! I have plugged the shield on 3 different TV :
a 720p one ; a 1080p TV; a 4K TV. On the 720p TV, the Shield can only work at 1080p which means non native resolution and big visible pixels.
On the 1080p TV, the Shield will only work a 4K resolution with reduced refresh rate (24Hz)… which sucks cause you can spot the big pixels from your couch and refresh rate make it looks “slow” or laggy.</description></item><item><title>Kodi beginner's guide</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 10:58:20 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_beginner_guide.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>As a great alternative to popcorn time, I am going to share with you a nice Kodi beginner’s guide.
How to install Kodi Browse to official Kodi website, and download the version of your liking (ie. Windows or Mac OS). Click here in order to get directly there!
Here is a little video to help you :
Once Kodi is installed, it is time to set up the “appropriate” addons.</description></item><item><title>Kodi Genesis tips and tricks</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:00:52 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_genesis_tips.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Genesis is a great add-on that let’s you stream movies and TV Shows under Kodi, let me share with you some great Genesis tips and tricks.
Disclaimer : streaming movies and TV shows might be illegal in your country, be sure to comply with local laws.
Genesis Subtitles Did you know that you could enable automatic subtitles in Genesis? Yup! In order to do so, just navigate to the Video Add-ons &gt; Genesis &gt; Tools, this is the where Genesis is configured, and tweaked.]]></description></item><item><title>Kodi SuperRepo, enhance Kodi!</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-superrepo-enhance-kodi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 20:44:36 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-superrepo-enhance-kodi/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_superrepo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The SuperRepo will enhance Kodi, allowing you to add and keep up-to-date thousands of add-ons.
How to install SuperRepo on Kodi Go to Kodi Settings &gt; File manager :
Select Add source :
Enter the following URL, “http://SRP.nu” (without quotes) :
Once done, it should look like this (notice SRP as name of media source) :
Now go to Settings &gt; Add-ons :
Then choose Install from zip, browse to the SRP repo you just added until, you see something like below :]]></description></item><item><title>Install Kodi on Windows 10</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 08:41:01 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-kodi-on-windows-10/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/install_kodi_win_10.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>The new Windows is here, please follow our latest video in order to install Kodi on Windows 10.
Install Kodi on Windows 10 This is pretty easy, as usual follow these few steps:
Go to kodi.tv Downloads page; Download the required version; Install it by clicking “Next”; Run and enjoy! Or else… You could also check our Kodi Beginner’s Guide for more detailed and advanced setup.</description></item><item><title>Is Kodi 4K ready?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/is-kodi-4k-ready/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 12:21:10 +0100</pubDate><author>Auteur</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/is-kodi-4k-ready/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_4k_rdy.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 1 of 1 in the series 4K
#4K display are becoming more and more affordable, but are they worth it? More importantly, what is really 4K and what are their pros and cons? And finally is #Kodi 4K ready? Let’s find out.
What is 4K? 4K is the “new resolution in town”. In order to understand 4K resolution, we have to understand what resolution is. According to Wikipedia, display resolution is “is the number of distinct pixels in each dimension that can be displayed”.</description></item></channel></rss>