<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>popcorn time - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/popcorn-time/</link><description>popcorn time - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 10:27:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/popcorn-time/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Popcorn time is dead... time to switch to Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead...-time-to-switch-to-kodi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 10:27:24 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead...-time-to-switch-to-kodi/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/10/rip.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Dear all,</p>
<h2 id="popcorn-timehttpswwwmasoopycomtagpopcorn-time-has-closed"><a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/popcorn-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#Popcorn Time</a> has closed</h2>
<p>Sad news, <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/popcorn-time-chaos-triggers-more-downtime-151023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Popcorn Time is dead</a>. Popcorn Time was a great software, however due its P2P nature, it was not safe <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/why-you-should-use-kodi-instead-of-popcorn-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">as I explained</a> a few weeks ago which probably lead to its death. Fear not, there are alternatives, and the best one is right here on this site.</p>
<h2 id="the-popcorn-time-alternative">The Popcorn time alternative</h2>
<p>The alternative is <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#Kodi</a> along with a good streaming plugin such as Genesis. Is is really easy to set up and can be done in a few steps that are already covered on this website on the following 2 articles.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-install-kodi-in-windows/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Install Kodi</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-stream-tv-shows-and-movies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Install Genesis</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Just follow through the first and then proceed to the second article and you will be set.</p>
<p>This method will allow you to stream movies and TV Shows exactly like Popcorn Time (minus the interface which will be different) and very important, it’ll be a lot safer.</p>
<p>It’s time to keep up your couch’s potatoes skill.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Popcorn Time is not safe, use Kodi as an alternative</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-not-safe-use-kodi-as-an-alternative/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 14:38:12 +0200</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-not-safe-use-kodi-as-an-alternative/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/09/popcorn.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>You have probably heard of <a href="https://popcorntime.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Popcorn time</a>. It is a great piece of software allowing you to stream Movies and TV Shows. However, <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/popcorn-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#Popcorn Time</a> is not safe, you should use <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#Kodi</a> as an alternative. Here is why.</p>
<p>Kodi, thanks to some <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-stream-tv-shows-and-movies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">nifty plugins</a> can allow you to stream movies and TV shows, just like Popcorn time. There is however one big difference.</p>
<p>Kodi streams its data directly from “established” websites, this is what we call “direct download” or direct streaming. When you watch a movies, only you, the website owner and your ISP know what you are doing. If streaming such data is illegal in your country, then you want the least people to know what you are doing.</p>
<p>Popcorn time on the other hand, is a P2P system based on torrent’s files. It means the data you are streaming is shared by many people (can be up to several hundreds people, even more technically). In the end, you, your ISP, and everyone “sharing” the file know what you are doing. Among those people, some will be because they want to watch it like, some others just want to help and keep “offering” movies to everyone, and some others might be here only to “spy on you”.</p>
<p>To sum this up, Popcorn Time is not the safe to stream movies, and I’d avoid using it. Also please remember that streaming movies you don’t own the rights for is probably illegal wherever you live.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>