<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>4K - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/4k/</link><description>4K - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:05:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/4k/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Nvidia Shield sucks?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:05:22 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/Nvidia-Shield-TV.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Yes, it is true. I think the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00U33Q940?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=6738&amp;tag=kodi-xbmc-20&amp;creativeASIN=B00U33Q940" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Nvidia Shield</a> sucks!</p>
<h2 id="to-be-4k-or-not-to-be">To be 4K or not to be</h2>
<p>First of, resolution ! I have plugged the shield on 3 different TV :</p>
<ul>
<li>a 720p one ;</li>
<li>a 1080p TV;</li>
<li>a 4K TV.</li>
</ul>
<p>On the 720p TV, the Shield can only work at 1080p which means non native resolution and big visible pixels.</p>
<p>On the 1080p TV, the Shield will only work a 4K resolution with reduced refresh rate (24Hz)… which sucks cause you can spot the big pixels from your couch and refresh rate make it looks “slow” or laggy.</p>
<p>Here is a picture of a 1080p TV with 4K resolution at 60Hz, not definitely not usable :</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now, same 1080p TV but 4K @ 24hz :</p>
<p></p>
<p>On the 4K, it works as it is supposed to. But honestly, sitting on your couch a few meters away, it is hard to tell the difference between a 4K Shield TV vs a Raspberry Pi 2 1080p setup.</p>
<p>Without a 4K display, you will get worse graphics for 5 times the price of a rpi2. So, yes the Nvidia Shield sucks with non native 4K displays.</p>
<h2 id="the-gamepad-is-well-not-for-gamers">The gamepad is… well not for gamers</h2>
<p>Gamepad is pretty big, fat an heavier than any other gamepad. Holding it in your hands for a long time will be exhausting.</p>
<p>Let’s compare sizes on a picture :</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now about the weight :</p>
<ul>
<li>Shield gamepad : 315g</li>
<li>Xbox 360 PC pad : 250g (310g with the whole cable)</li>
<li>PS4 : 220g</li>
<li>PS3: 195g</li>
</ul>
<p>Please note that weights have been rounded to the next upper value. The gamepad alone is heavier than the old gen Xbox 360 pad with its cable… and lot fatter to as the picture attests.</p>
<p>Once again again, the Nvidia Shield sucks as it makes you lift weights while you should be playing.</p>
<h2 id="gaming-platform-not-so-much">Gaming platform… not so much</h2>
<p>I am not sure what people are supposed to do with a Shield. Media Center ? Not really when you have Android TV stick and/or ChromeCast devices that are way cheaper, plug and play and run Kodi.</p>
<p>I believe the Shield should be good gaming platform, but no the Nvidia shield sucks at gaming too.</p>
<p>Android games ? No thanks, they work OK, but again if you want to play Android game buy a stick or an Ouya console. A part from a very short list of titles, you’ll be able to play the same games.</p>
<p><a href="http://shield.nvidia.com/game-stream" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Geforce Game-Stream</a> ? Well, maybe, but not today. This point could be pretty interesting. It allows you to stream almost any game from your running PC to your TV / couch setup. After playing with a it a little, I have to say that it is far from perfect. Some games don’t play along, and it lags quite often, I used wired networking only. Actually, this point is not that bad, it kinda works. However, for the tech knowhow there is a free implementation called <a href="http://moonlight-stream.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Moonlight</a> and it happens to work OK on a $40 RPI2. Moonlight is not as good as Geforce Game-Stream, but is playable most of the time.</p>
<p><a href="http://shield.nvidia.com/games/geforce-now" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Nvidia Geforce Now</a>, for about ten bucks a month, you can rent games and play them on your shield without having to use a computer. Everything from the game is “calculated” on Nvidia cloud servers and you just stream it to your couch. However, you’ll need the very HIGH bandwith (we are talking about 50Mbit/s for 1080p @ 60Hz as per <a href="http://shield.nvidia.com/support/geforce-now/system-requirements/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">official requirements</a>) in order to be able to play any game. Moreover, most recent games can’t really be rented but have to be completely bought.. and you’ll sometimes get a key for your regular PC but not always. If you have a gaming computer, it is still better to buy the regular game and stream it thanks to Geforce Game-Stream.</p>
<p>Last but not least, playing old console games. I have already started a serie about <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/the-original-xbmc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">retrogaming</a>. The Shield can allow you to run emulators, however the good emulators (<a href="https://play.google.com/store/search?q=.emu&amp;c=apps&amp;docType=1&amp;sp=CAFiBgoELmVtdXoFGADAAQKKAQIIAQ%3D%3D:S:ANO1ljJz6Ik" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">.emu from Robert Broglia</a>) are not free. They are around $5 each… and there is not many frontend, or they are not very nice looking. A “frontend” allows you to have a nice looking and consistent experience : all emulator are accessible from the same menu with a nice GUI. This is far more entertaining than the Android’s way offered by the Shield.</p>
<p>A nice emulation frontend, <a href="http://www.recalbox.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Recalbox</a> :</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q5UYxuzKEec?feature=oembed" width="640"></iframe>
<p>Android emulators :</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IJEwiHBwKoM?feature=oembed" width="640"></iframe>
<h2 id="yeah-nvidia-shield-sucksreally">Yeah, Nvidia shield sucks…really</h2>
<p>And I am really disappointed to say so. I bought it during a the black Friday and I was really hoping to find a great device, since I read many great reviews, but I am actually really disappointed. I am sending it back to Amazon. I’ll keep using the RPI2 with Recalbox. As for a media center solution, you could still use a regular Kodi installation with the right add-ons for streaming, as per our <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Kodi Beginner’s Guide</a>.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Is Kodi 4K ready?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/is-kodi-4k-ready/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 12:21:10 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/is-kodi-4k-ready/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_4k_rdy.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>This entry is part 1 of 1 in the series <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/series/4k/" title="4K" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">4K</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/4k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#4K</a> display are becoming more and more affordable, but are they worth it? More importantly, what is really 4K and what are their pros and cons? And finally is <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">#Kodi</a> 4K ready? Let’s find out.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-4k">What is 4K?</h2>
<p>4K  is the “new resolution in town”. In order to understand 4K resolution, we have to understand what resolution is. According to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Display_resolution" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Wikipedia</a>, display resolution is “is the number of distinct pixels in each dimension that can be displayed”. A very common resolution nowadays is Full HD (also referred as 1080p). It means that an image using this resolution is 1920 pixels in width by 1080 pixels in height.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now, the latest 4K resolution, is 4 times this size, which is 3840 pixels in width by 2160 pixels in height. Let’s do some simple maths :</p>
<p>FHD –&gt; 1920*1080 = 2,073,600</p>
<p>4K    –&gt; 3840*2160 = 8,294,400</p>
<p>then 4K / FHD —&gt; 8,294,400 / 2,073,600 = 4</p>
<p>Basically, it means it 4K times “superior” to Full HD resolution.</p>
<h2 id="pros-and-cons-of-4k">Pros and cons of 4K</h2>
<p>Now that we know what is 4K, let’s focus on the main advantages and disadvantages of the 4K resolution.</p>
<h3 id="advantage-of-4k">Advantage of 4K</h3>
<ul>
<li>Higher resolution means bigger level of details. 4K images / movies will look more “smooth” with less visible “pixellated areas”.</li>
<li>True 4K content, really looks awesome, it is, subjectively, clearer, sharper and nicer.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="disadvantages-of-4k">Disadvantages of 4K</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lack of content: most content is not yet 4K ready. However, some providers such as Netflix are adding more and more 4K content to their library.</li>
<li>Bigger file size. As we said, 4K is 4 times “superior” in quality, it is also way bigger to download.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now that we’ve seen the main advantages and disadvantages of 4K, let’s answer our initial question.</p>
<h2 id="is-kodi-4k-ready">Is Kodi 4K ready?</h2>
<p>Well, actually… sorry for the answer but it’ll be a yes and a no at the same time.</p>
<p>Yes, Kodi is 4K ready (as long as your hardware is, more on that coming in a dedicated post). Skins will “auto resize” to the 4K resolution from 1080p which is as easy as doubling height and width (which in the end results in a 4 times factor) of every images from the skins.</p>
<p>Moreover, Kodi will upscale lower resolution’s content to 4K, and with the proper settings (more on that coming in another post as well) you could, subjectively again, notice a better overall quality from your content.</p>
<p>And no, Kodi is not 4K ready. Indeed, the skins are “just” 1080p yet, and are not natively drawn with the 4K resolution (whereas PS4 and Xbox One skins are). In practice, it works really fine. In theory, it shows a lack of interest for the format. Last but not least, 4K content is awfully missing (not Kodi’s fault here), and in order to really enjoy Kodi in 4K, we really need quality 4K content.</p>
<p>Now that we have shown you a brief tour of 4K, it’s up to you to decide whether or not you want to go down that road. If you choose to go, keep reading us as this article is the first of a series about Kodi and 4K.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>