<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>kodi genesis tips and tricks - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</link><description>kodi genesis tips and tricks - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:00:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kodi Genesis tips and tricks</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:00:52 +0100</pubDate><author>Denis G.</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_genesis_tips.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Genesis is a great add-on that let’s you stream movies and TV Shows under Kodi, let me share with you some great Genesis tips and tricks.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer : streaming movies and TV shows might be illegal in your country, be sure to comply with local laws.</em></p>
<h2 id="genesis-subtitles">Genesis Subtitles</h2>
<p>Did you know that you could enable automatic subtitles in Genesis? Yup! In order to do so, just navigate to the Video Add-ons &gt; Genesis &gt; Tools, this is the where Genesis is configured, and tweaked.</p>
<p></p>
<p>When I talk about Genesis settings, this is the right place, and it looks like the picture below.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now select the Settings : subtitles line, and configure it to suit your likings.</p>
<p></p>
<h2 id="share-genesis-library-across-devices">Share Genesis library across devices</h2>
<p>If you are using Kodi on several devices, then you might consider sharing your Genesis library across several devices. This is really easy, let’s do it!</p>
<p>Go to Genesis settings, as explained above.</p>
<p>Then, Library Settings,</p>
<p></p>
<p>and edit the Movies and TV Shows paths in order to use a network location (eg. your NAS), as shown below with before / after picture.</p>
<p>Before change (please note the default path: special://…) :</p>
<p></p>
<p>After change (please note that I am using NFS share on my NAS) :</p>
<p></p>
<p>Highlight Movies folder, hit C on your keyboard (or right click), select “Set content”, and choose the Movies scraper you want to use.</p>
<p>Repeat for the TV Shows folder with the wanted TV Shows scraper.</p>
<p>Now hit the Update folders button, that’s it!</p>
<h2 id="more-genesis-tips-and-tricks">More Genesis tips and tricks</h2>
<p>There is even more Genesis tips and tricks, here is a quick list.</p>
<p>Notify trakt.tv of your watching by adding your trakt.tv credentials in Gensis settings as shown below.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Edit source priority in order to use the Auto play feature. Once you have used Genesis a little, you’ll notice that some source are more reliable than some others. Write down the sources that works well for you and increase their priority in the menu shown below.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Feel free to share you own Genesis tips and tricks with us in the comment section of this post.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>