<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>wiki - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/wiki/</link><description>wiki - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 08:48:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/wiki/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manage VMware snapshots with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/manage-vmware-snapshots-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 08:48:46 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/manage-vmware-snapshots-with-powercli/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2018/12/Manage-VMware-snapshots-with-PowerCLI.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Manually taking a snapshot under VMware is easy : connect to the HTML5 Web UI, find the server from the list, right click, select Snapshot, Name it&hellip; However, when you have to do it several times in a row, it becomes really frustrating. Let&rsquo;s see how to improve that.
Here comes PowerCLI VMware released an awesome (and I am Linux guy) tool to manage your virtual machines from the command line.]]></description></item><item><title>Sending text messages from your computer</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 11:12:57 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/sending-text-messages-from-your-computer/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/send_text_from_pc.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Do you hate touchscreen? I sure do! More than touchscreen, I hate when I have to write something using a touch screen. This is why, I have been trying and using different solutions that allows me to send text messages from my computer with a real (mechanical) keyboard!
Foreword Please note that this guide is based on Android phones and is desktop &ldquo;OS&rdquo; agnostic.
If you are using Apple phones and computers, then have a look here.]]></description></item><item><title>Accessing the BIOS</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/accessing-the-bios/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 10:44:13 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/accessing-the-bios/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/bios.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this quick guide, let&rsquo;s see how to access the BIOS of any system.
What is the BIOS? Basically, the BIOS is the place where you can configure how the hardware works (like speed of the FAN), and how you computer boots (such as booting an external USB disk instead of the internal disk).
It is pretty common to access the BIOS (or better, the boot menu, which is related to the BIOS) when you can to install a new OS, or reinstall your system.]]></description></item><item><title>How to burn an iso file to USB stick</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-burn-an-iso-file-to-usb-stick/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 06:52:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-burn-an-iso-file-to-usb-stick/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/burn_iso_2_usb.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Let&rsquo;s see how to &ldquo;burn&rdquo; an image file (or .iso file) to an USB stick and make it bootable.
NB: please note that in every case, all the data on your USB stick will be erased!!
Windows Under Windows, simply download, install and run Rufus. Then follow the on-screen instructions.
Macos Much like Windows, on Macos, you can use a tool called Etcher and follow the on-screen instructions.
Linux Now, it becomes a little harder / funnier.]]></description></item><item><title>How to create a bootable Windows 10 USB stick</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-create-a-bootable-windows-10-usb-stick/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 16:05:45 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/how-to-create-a-bootable-windows-10-usb-stick/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/boot_usb_win_10.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Maybe you bought a new computer and reinstall it from scratch, or maybe you plan to sell your current computer, or maybe you just want to install Windows 10 as a new OS. In Any case, creating a bootable Windows USB stick will allow you to do so.
It could be harder This might sound scary, but it as actually very easy. However, please note that, for this method to work you&rsquo;ll need to proceed from a Windows 10 computer.]]></description></item><item><title>Automatically run Kodi at boot</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automatically-run-kodi-at-boot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 09:49:06 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automatically-run-kodi-at-boot/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>You have some hardware dedicated to Kodi and wish to create a “clean” media center solution hooked to your TV? Great idea! Find out how to automatically run Kodi at boot on any platform.
Automatically run Kodi at boot with Windows This method is similar to the Steam Shell mode.. but with Kodi.
First of all, make sure you can can log into the Windows desktop automatically. In order to do so:</description></item></channel></rss>