<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>kodi - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/kodi/</link><description>kodi - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 16:04:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/kodi/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back to the sources : Kodi on Xbox One</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/back-to-the-sources-kodi-on-xbox-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 16:04:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/back-to-the-sources-kodi-on-xbox-one/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/xbone.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Almost 15 years ago, XBMC was created. Like today, it was a media center allowing you to watch your media, listen to your music and even playing old school games and Xbox games. All of this on place, and all of this on one specific hardware : the first generation Microsoft Xbox.
A new era Then the Xbox 360 has been released but Kodi was never part of it. In 2013, the latest and curren gen Xbox, the One was released.</description></item><item><title>Synchronize your media with Kodi Trakt plugin</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/synchronize-your-media-with-kodi-trakt-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 06:13:46 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/synchronize-your-media-with-kodi-trakt-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/trakt.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Trakt.tv is website dedicated to movies and TV Shows. It allows you to manage all your media needs: keeping track of what you have already watched and what you to plan to watch. Thanks to this guide, we will see how you can automatically synchronize everything you watch with Kodi Trakt plugin.
Install Kodi Trakt plugin From Kodi home screen, browse to the search button (top left hand side corner):</description></item><item><title>Access Tunein Radio with Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/access-tunein-radio-with-kodi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:27:49 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/access-tunein-radio-with-kodi/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/tunein.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Tunein allows you to listen to both regular and web radio from Internet: be it live, and from old automatically recorded podcasts. Orginally it is a website, but let’s se how to use Tunein radio with Kodi!
Installing Tunein Radio for Kodi  Download the latest zip file from here. Launch Kodi Browse to Add-on &gt; Add-on Browser Select Install from zip file Choose the file you just downloaded Wait for install to complete Done !]]></description></item><item><title>Resume video playing with Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/resume-video-playing-with-kodi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 15:29:33 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/resume-video-playing-with-kodi/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/resume_video_kodi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Recently, I noticed a weird behaviour where Kodi no longer asks me to resume playing. Let me show you how to force that feature so that it works again.
Get your hands dirty Unfortunately you will have to go inside the advancedsettings.xml file.
Locate the file in question and open it with a regular text editor (like notepad, not Word). Depending on your system, here is where you’ll find the file:</description></item><item><title>Automatic subtitles download Kodi 17</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/automatic-subtitles-download-kodi-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 13:13:35 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/automatic-subtitles-download-kodi-17/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/auto_sub_dl_kodi_17.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Kodi is a “do it all” media center, and that’s why we love it so much. Automatic subtitles download Kodi 17 is one of those great features. Making it a more “Netflix like” experience.
Same same, but different We already talk about this for previous version, but it changed a little with the latest Kodi version. This is due to the fact that Kodi 17 has brought a new skin. Don’t fear and follow the guide, this is going to be a easy job.</description></item><item><title>Kodi 17 is finally available with a brand new interface</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-17-is-finally-available-with-a-brand-new-interface/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 15:14:57 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-17-is-finally-available-with-a-brand-new-interface/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2016/03/Estuary-001.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>After years of using the exact same interface, Kodi has now released a new one! It is called Estuary and it is shipped with the latest Kodi 17.
Time to upgrade! Linux users If you are already using Kodi under Linux, it is time to update your packages in order to pull Kodi 17 version and benefit from the new interface.
Depending on your distribution you can enter the following command in a terminal window:</description></item><item><title>Install Trakt add-on for Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/install-trakt-add-on-for-kodi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:13:24 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/install-trakt-add-on-for-kodi/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_trakt.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Are you following so many TV Shows that you often lost track of what you’ve already watched? Or maybe you simply want to know when the next episode will be? If you answered yes, at least once, then I check Trakt add-on for Kodi.
Trakt Trakt is a great website. It allow you to manage you Movies and TV Show libraries. It has several options, such as creating lists for already watched media, or media to watch, etc.</description></item><item><title>Fix out of sync subtitles with Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/fix-out-of-sync-subtitles-with-kodi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 16:04:58 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/fix-out-of-sync-subtitles-with-kodi/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/fix_oos_sub_kodi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Oh, man! #Kodi #subtitles out of sync?! Yes it happens! Most of the time it can be fixed thanks to the GUI, but sometimes you want to be able to resync them for more or less than 10 seconds, here is what you need to do.
File to edit Locate advancedsettings.xml. Based on your OS, it will be in the following locations:
Windows Click Start Menu, then Run and enter :</description></item><item><title>What is video game streaming?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/what-is-video-game-streaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 08:45:22 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/what-is-video-game-streaming/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/game_streaming.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Nowadays, one can stream a whole lot of different, more especially music and video. Although it is “pretty” new, video game streaming is becoming more and more present.
A short technical presentation of video game streaming Let’s start by defining what a video game is. I can see two big categories of game :
small games: the ones you play inside your browser, on Facebook, etc. regular games : the ones you play on a console, or the one you have to install on your computer and require dedicated hardware such as a good video card.</description></item><item><title>Genesis alternatives, what are your choices?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/genesis-alternatives-what-are-your-choices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 11:32:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/genesis-alternatives-what-are-your-choices/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/genesis_alternatives.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>One of my favourite add-ons is no longer supported by its famous developer, Lambda. Let’s find out valuable Genesis alternatives for you Kodi installation.
Genesis is dead? Yes it is.. and this is sad… However alternatives exist !
As of today, Genesis is dead. Thanks a lot to this author for all the great work he did for us all.
Let’s now focus on a few great alternatives, before something even greater comes out of the dead Genesis.</description></item></channel></rss>