<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>genesis - Tag - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/tags/genesis/</link><description>genesis - Tag - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 11:32:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/tags/genesis/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Genesis alternatives, what are your choices?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/genesis-alternatives-what-are-your-choices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 11:32:00 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/genesis-alternatives-what-are-your-choices/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/genesis_alternatives.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>One of my favourite add-ons is no longer supported by its famous developer, Lambda. Let’s find out valuable Genesis alternatives for you Kodi installation.</p>
<h2 id="genesis-is-dead">Genesis is dead?</h2>
<p></p>
<p>Yes it is.. and this is sad… However alternatives exist !</p>
<p>As of today, Genesis is dead. Thanks a lot to this author for all the great work he did for us all.</p>
<p>Let’s now focus on a few great alternatives, before something even greater comes out of the dead Genesis.</p>
<h2 id="a-few-genesis-alternatives">A few Genesis alternatives</h2>
<p>EDIT : March 5th 2016 –&gt; Exodus add-on has been released. It is from lambda, the Genesis creator and it is awesome. He promised us a new add-on and it now there. <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/exodus-new-genesis-reborn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Check our guide to install the Exodus add-on on Kodi.</a></p>
<h3 id="salts">SALTS</h3>
<p>Stream All The Sources, will allow you to stream Movies and TV Shows. It aslo includes <a href="http://trakt.tv/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">trakt.tv</a> integration (via an API) so that you can keep track of the watched media and create watch list.</p>
<h3 id="gomovies">GoMovies</h3>
<p>From the author GoMovies, might be the perfect and “official” Genesis replacement.</p>
<h3 id="ororotv">Ororo.tv</h3>
<p>Also from the same author of Genesis, Ororo.tv is a valid alternative to Genesis.</p>
<h3 id="istream">iStream</h3>
<p>There is also iStream, that will allow you so stream Movies and TV Shows, <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/streaming-on-kodi-istream-vs-genesis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">check my little comparison</a>(VS Genesis) from a few months ago.</p>
<p>Don’t fear, there is a handful of Genesis alternatives. Let’s name a few of them.</p>
<h2 id="quick-install-guide">Quick install guide</h2>
<p>In Kodi, installing an add-on is pretty straightforward, it is a simple process :</p>
<ol>
<li>Install the SuperRepo add-on (<a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-superrepo-enhance-kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">see our step by step guide</a>) ;</li>
<li>Browse to Add-ons &gt; Repositories &gt; SuperRepo &gt; Video Add-ons ;</li>
<li>Find the add-on by its name, and install it.</li>
</ol>
]]></description></item><item><title>Kodi beginner's guide</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 10:58:20 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-beginners-guide/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_beginner_guide.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>As a great alternative to <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead-time-to-switch-to-kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">popcorn time</a>, I am going to share with you a nice Kodi beginner’s guide.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-install-kodi">How to install Kodi</h2>
<p>Browse to official Kodi website, and download the version of your liking (ie. Windows or Mac OS). <a href="http://kodi.tv/download/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click here in order to get directly there!</a></p>
<p>Here is a little video to help you :</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vKzOYtXu7L4?feature=oembed" width="640"></iframe>
<p>Once Kodi is installed, it is time to set up the “appropriate” addons.</p>
<h2 id="popcorn-time-alternative--the-kodi-streaming-add-ons">Popcorn time alternative – the Kodi streaming add-ons</h2>
<p><em>Disclaimer : please remember that streaming movies and TV shows might be against your local laws.</em></p>
<p>In order to install the SuperRepo, follow the steps below :</p>
<ul>
<li>Go to Settings &gt; File manager and add a source. In the source name enter “<a href="http://srp.nu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://srp.nu</a>” (without the quote) and name it SRP.</li>
<li>Go to Settings &gt; Add-ons &gt; Add from zip file</li>
<li>Select the SRP you just added, browse to the current Kodi version (Isengard at the time of writing), and All add-ons and install the SuperRepo Isengard Repository</li>
<li>Once you have installed the SuperRepo Isengard Repository, go back to Add-on manager.</li>
<li>Select Add from repository &gt; Select the SuperRepo one and browse to Video add-ons</li>
<li>In this HUGE list, select Genesis and click Install.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-superrepo-enhance-kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A more detailed guide can be found here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="configure-genesis-to-enjoy-a-great-streaming-experience">Configure Genesis to enjoy a great streaming experience</h2>
<p>Genesis is a great add-on! You can configure it so that you can share your “watch list” across multiple devices, you can automatically download subtitles, and populate your videos library with you favourite shows, and much more.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-tricks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Here are some great tips to enhance your Genesis experience</a>, and find out even more in our free PDF guide.</p>
<h2 id="get-the-full-kodi-beginners-guide-for-free-right-now">Get the full Kodi Beginner’s guide for free, right now!</h2>
<p>In order to make it easy and portable for anyone, we have written a full 24 pages PDF guide, explaining with many details, pictures and step by step how to setup the perfect Kodi streaming experience.</p>
<p>Please help us, by sharing this content and get the full uncensored guide for free, right here :</p>
<p><a href="/images/2015/11/Kodi_Beginners_Guide.pdf" rel="">Kodi_Beginners_Guide</a></p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Kodi Genesis tips and tricks</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:00:52 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/kodi_genesis_tips.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Genesis is a great add-on that let’s you stream movies and TV Shows under Kodi, let me share with you some great Genesis tips and tricks.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer : streaming movies and TV shows might be illegal in your country, be sure to comply with local laws.</em></p>
<h2 id="genesis-subtitles">Genesis Subtitles</h2>
<p>Did you know that you could enable automatic subtitles in Genesis? Yup! In order to do so, just navigate to the Video Add-ons &gt; Genesis &gt; Tools, this is the where Genesis is configured, and tweaked.</p>
<p></p>
<p>When I talk about Genesis settings, this is the right place, and it looks like the picture below.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now select the Settings : subtitles line, and configure it to suit your likings.</p>
<p></p>
<h2 id="share-genesis-library-across-devices">Share Genesis library across devices</h2>
<p>If you are using Kodi on several devices, then you might consider sharing your Genesis library across several devices. This is really easy, let’s do it!</p>
<p>Go to Genesis settings, as explained above.</p>
<p>Then, Library Settings,</p>
<p></p>
<p>and edit the Movies and TV Shows paths in order to use a network location (eg. your NAS), as shown below with before / after picture.</p>
<p>Before change (please note the default path: special://…) :</p>
<p></p>
<p>After change (please note that I am using NFS share on my NAS) :</p>
<p></p>
<p>Highlight Movies folder, hit C on your keyboard (or right click), select “Set content”, and choose the Movies scraper you want to use.</p>
<p>Repeat for the TV Shows folder with the wanted TV Shows scraper.</p>
<p>Now hit the Update folders button, that’s it!</p>
<h2 id="more-genesis-tips-and-tricks">More Genesis tips and tricks</h2>
<p>There is even more Genesis tips and tricks, here is a quick list.</p>
<p>Notify trakt.tv of your watching by adding your trakt.tv credentials in Gensis settings as shown below.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Edit source priority in order to use the Auto play feature. Once you have used Genesis a little, you’ll notice that some source are more reliable than some others. Write down the sources that works well for you and increase their priority in the menu shown below.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Feel free to share you own Genesis tips and tricks with us in the comment section of this post.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Streaming on Kodi : iStream vs Genesis</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/streaming-on-kodi-istream-vs-genesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:48:04 +0200</pubDate><dc:creator>Denis G.</dc:creator><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/streaming-on-kodi-istream-vs-genesis/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/05/Genesis_vs_istream.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>It has been a long time without posting. Today, I am back, and I hope I’ll be able to keep this website updated.</p>
<p>Lately, I have totally changed my way of watching media. For years, I used to get my media from newsgroups and store them and my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00EN1BZL0?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=6738&amp;tag=kodi-xbmc-20&amp;creativeASIN=B00EN1BZL0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">custom built NAS</a>. Since I discovered streaming plugins, I no longer store media, so that I can focus on backing up my data from my several computers to the NAS.</p>
<p>I found that, in same the same way “there is an app for this”, there is a plugin for each case.</p>
<h3 id="streaming-old-tv-shows">Streaming old TV Shows</h3>
<p>By old I mean no longer running TV Shows, or first seasons of a long run TV Show (eg: The Simpsons). When I want to stream this kind of media, I’ll go with <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/kodi-genesis-stream-tv-shows-and-movies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">genesis</a>. It is fast, has many feeds, and good working search funtion that, most of the time, directly find what I am looking for. Whereas, <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/istream/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#istream</a> will return many, many results, and the right one is often lost in the middle of non relevant answers.</p>
<h3 id="streaming-running-tv-shows">Streaming running TV Shows</h3>
<p>When you are downloading media with soft like sabnzbd, or nzbget, you get notified in <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/kodi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#kodi</a> / <a href="https://www.masoopy.com/tag/xbmc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#xbmc</a> when a new file has been added. Everything is automated, and it is great (to be lazy). Now, with the streaming, you no longer have the notification when a new show is available for streaming, unless you subscribe to different services in order to “track” shows.</p>
<p>However, thanks to <a href="http://xunitytalk.com/forum.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iStream</a> and the subscription function (I’ll add an article about this later on) you can now keep track of all the new TV shows as soon as they become available. Definately a must have!</p>
<h3 id="streaming-movies">Streaming Movies</h3>
<p>On the movie side, I hate screeners, and I don’t keep myself updated about latest and/or popular movies. I rearely watch movies, and I decide to do so, I just want to watch some cover and select one from the cover and/or title.</p>
<p>For this kind if watching, I am using <a href="http://xunitytalk.com/forum.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iStream</a> as well. It has a great function, that allows me to find movies based of Box Office by years. This means, that I’ll never select the “latest” or current year movies in order to avoid ugly screeners.</p>
<p>This way, I have good quality movies and at the same time “popular” movies. Perfect for me!</p>
<p>I hope, it will help you slack in front of “TV”.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>