<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>hardware - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/hardware/</link><description>hardware - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 16:48:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/hardware/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All your devices are belong to Ubiquity</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/all-your-devices-are-belong-to-ubiquity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 16:48:01 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/all-your-devices-are-belong-to-ubiquity/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/unifi.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I love tech and I love to try new tech stuff. Recently, I have been playing with some network gear from Ubiquiti. For a reasonable price, you&rsquo;ll get enterprise grade gear. Is it really that good? Let&rsquo;s check my non-unboxing review.
A bit of background I am a frequent reader of Mr Troy Hunt and when I read his article a few years ago about the Unifi suite that made want to try it again, a little.]]></description></item><item><title>Shield TV 2017, let's take a fresh start</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/shield-tv-2017-lets-take-a-fresh-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 08:25:14 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/shield-tv-2017-lets-take-a-fresh-start/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/shield_2017.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>After criticizing like crazy the first Shield TV, I decided to buy the Shield 2017 and give it a try.
Only morons never change their minds Let&rsquo;s say it straight away, I have now adopted the Shield TV 2017!
I also have the feeling that Nvidia also decided to slightly change their product. They are now offering 2 &ldquo;versions&rdquo; of the box :
 a multimedia version, sold only with the remote ; a gamer version, sold with an additional controller.]]></description></item><item><title>GPD Pocket, a very small but yet powerful laptop</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/gpd-pocket-a-very-small-but-yet-powerful-laptop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 09:37:34 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/gpd-pocket-a-very-small-but-yet-powerful-laptop/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/gpd.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Let me present you my latest gadget, the GPD Pocket a full HD 7&quot; quad core laptop, with 8GB RAM and 128GB storage. It runs Windows 10 and more importantly (to me), it also runs Linux!
Quick specs  Intel Atom® x7-Z8750 Processor (quad core) 8GB RAM 128 GB storage (eeprom based) 7000 mAh battery (12 hours announced battery life) FHD 7&quot; touch screen (1920x1200)  Look and usage I love the look!]]></description></item><item><title>Current gen consoles are disappointing</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/current-gen-consoles-are-disappointing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 12:29:39 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/current-gen-consoles-are-disappointing/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2017/01/7439512656_ae58012e17_k.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>It has already been a bit more than 4 years now. Four years that the current gen consoles are disappointing.
A lost generation Since the begining, current gen consoles have been outdated. About around the same time, the 1st 4K TV was released, while the current gen consoles could hardly provide 1080p at only 30fps. While at the same time, the same games could be played with better graphics on a regular PC.</description></item><item><title>Android TV sucks</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/android-tv-sucks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 11:09:36 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/android-tv-sucks/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/12/AndroidRedTriangle.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>I have recently purchased a new TV, it is brand new, with a computer built-in and everything one could wish for… and I am proud to say it : my Android TV sucks!
What is an Android TV? Basically, it is a TV with Android installed inside of it. This is like having a small computer built inside your TV and running the Android OS. It allows you to run several well known applications directly on your TV thanks to your remote.</description></item><item><title>Why Nvidia Shield sucks?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:05:22 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/why-nvidia-shield-sucks/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/Nvidia-Shield-TV.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Yes, it is true. I think the Nvidia Shield sucks!
To be 4K or not to be First of, resolution ! I have plugged the shield on 3 different TV :
a 720p one ; a 1080p TV; a 4K TV. On the 720p TV, the Shield can only work at 1080p which means non native resolution and big visible pixels.
On the 1080p TV, the Shield will only work a 4K resolution with reduced refresh rate (24Hz)… which sucks cause you can spot the big pixels from your couch and refresh rate make it looks “slow” or laggy.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 4 : OpenElec</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-4-openelec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 07:34:47 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-4-openelec/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>This entry is part 4 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
Last but not least, we’ll explain you how to install #OpenElec on your Pi!
Prepare before install Mandatory  Raspberry #Pi 2 Micro SD Card (&gt;512MB) Power Adapter (&gt;=1A) Micro USB Cable  Optional  Keyboard Mouse Remote WLAN Dongle Ethernet Cable Case  Steps  Download the ARMv7 Stable build from official site ; Extract it and navigate to extracted files and folder ; If using Linux or Mac Os, just run “create_sdcard” file, follow instructions and go to “Install OpenElec” part ; If using Windows, download win32diskimager and run it ; Select image file you just downloaded and point it to your SD card.]]></description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 3 : media center</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-3-media-center/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 07:34:41 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-3-media-center/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 3 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
Today we’ll talk about media center solutions for the Pis. Let’s go!
Media Center Distribution One of the most common use of the Raspberry #Pi 2 is to build a media center out of it. In order to so, one have access to several different “tools”. Let’s do a quick presentation.
#Raspbian This is a Linux, Debian based OS (aka distribution).</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 2 : different uses</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-2-different-uses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 06:04:51 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-2-different-uses/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 2 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
In the first part, we saw a brief presentation of the #Pi 2 hardware with some pictures. Now, in the sequel, we’ll see what you can do with a #Raspberry Pi 2.
Hardware applications You could build a Temperature and Humidity Sensor, in order to monitor room temperature or help you grow vegetables thanks to the readings.
If you are the gaming type, you could always build an Arcade Pi.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi 2 - Part 1 : Hardware</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-1-hardware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 07:01:06 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/raspberry-pi-2-part-1-hardware/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/06/raspberry.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This entry is part 1 of 4 in the series Raspberry Pi
In this first article, I’ll talk about the latest #Raspberry #Pi 2 hardware, and what you can do with it. In a latter post, I’ll detail various things you can do with your Pi 2, and eventually in a last article I’ll guide you through the full install process. Stay tuned!
Compared to the Raspberry Pi 1 it has:</description></item></channel></rss>