<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>apps - Category - Masoopy</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/categories/apps/</link><description>apps - Category - Masoopy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 09:58:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.masoopy.com/categories/apps/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Netflix now lets you download files to your external storage</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/netflix-now-lets-you-download-files-to-your-external-storage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 09:58:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/netflix-now-lets-you-download-files-to-your-external-storage/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/2021/02/netflix.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The latest version of Netflix finally allows you to download your media to the external storage of your devices.
Netflix allows you to download files to external storage Since its latest version, Netflix allows you to download files to external storage. This is a great and long awaited addition! Just head over the Google App store, and download the latest version of the application.
 Run the application; Then go to Settings &gt; Download location, and select your external storage.]]></description></item><item><title>Date Night : What should we watch tonight?</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/date-night-what-should-we-watch-tonight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 10:12:42 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/date-night-what-should-we-watch-tonight/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2021/02/date_night.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Have you ever struggled finding the perfect movie to watch? Thanks to Date Night, finally the answer to, “What should we watch tonight?”.
What should we watch tonight? Date Night helps allows you and your loved one to select each one a movie you like and in return will suggest a result that should suits both of you.
Let’s say you want to watch, Jaws and your wife wants to watch Notting Hill (yeah, that’s very cliché) :</description></item><item><title>Popcorn time is dead... time to switch to Kodi</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead...-time-to-switch-to-kodi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 10:27:24 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-dead...-time-to-switch-to-kodi/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/10/rip.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Dear all,
#Popcorn Time has closed Sad news, Popcorn Time is dead. Popcorn Time was a great software, however due its P2P nature, it was not safe as I explained a few weeks ago which probably lead to its death. Fear not, there are alternatives, and the best one is right here on this site.
The Popcorn time alternative The alternative is #Kodi along with a good streaming plugin such as Genesis.</description></item><item><title>Popcorn Time is not safe, use Kodi as an alternative</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-not-safe-use-kodi-as-an-alternative/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 14:38:12 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/popcorn-time-is-not-safe-use-kodi-as-an-alternative/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/09/popcorn.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>You have probably heard of Popcorn time. It is a great piece of software allowing you to stream Movies and TV Shows. However, #Popcorn Time is not safe, you should use #Kodi as an alternative. Here is why.
Kodi, thanks to some nifty plugins can allow you to stream movies and TV shows, just like Popcorn time. There is however one big difference.
Kodi streams its data directly from “established” websites, this is what we call “direct download” or direct streaming.</description></item><item><title>Yatse, the XBMC / Kodi remote</title><link>https://www.masoopy.com/yatse-the-xbmc-/-kodi-remote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 19:44:28 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://www.masoopy.com/yatse-the-xbmc-/-kodi-remote/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/2015/04/yatse.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>I personaly use a wireless “keyboard touchpad” as remote for my #Kodi box and I am very happy with it. This is a very basic, but it works, and it works really well.
However if you are looking for extra features then I highly recommend trying out Yatse.
Mainly, Yatse will allow you to browse your media collection, see fanarts, read movies / episodes summary, launch a media.
While playing any item and in addition to classic play/pause/forward/rewind/stop, you can manage subtitles (download, turn on/off, sync), modify audio (source, volume), and much more.</description></item></channel></rss>